MENU

[WEBTOON SHOP](https://shop.webtoon.com/) [Creators 101](https://www.webtoons.com/en/creators101/webtoon-canvas) [Publish](#) Log In

Close the Login window

Search

 _Search by Series Title or Creator_ _Search_ [Delete](#) _|_ [Close](#)

* * *

Privacy Policy
--------------

If you are accessing from France (Français), Indonesia (Indonesia), Taiwan (中文(繁體)) Thailand(ภาษาไทย) respective regional Privacy Policy will apply.

### WEBTOON™ PRIVACY POLICY HIGHLIGHTS

Last Updated: March 26, 2024

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. (including its affiliates, hereinafter together referred to as **“we”**, **“our”** or **"us"**) respect your concerns about privacy. This Privacy Policy applies to the personal information we collect through WEBTOON application and/or website, WEBTOON TRANSLATE and CANVAS (collectively **“Services”**).

#### OVERVIEW OF PRIVACY POLICY

In this Privacy Policy, we describe the types of personal information we process through the Services, how we may use the information, with whom we may share it and the choices available to you regarding use of the information and exercise of your rights. We also describe the measures we take to safeguard the information and tell you how to contact us about our privacy practices. Below you will find a summary of the key messages contained in our Privacy Policy. For more detailed information on how we process your information, please click on the headings or continue to read below.

### WEBTOON™ PRIVACY POLICY

#### 1\. Data Controllers

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. and WEBTOON Entertainment Inc. share joint controllership for processing personal information and share information as joint controllers of your personal information to provide Services efficiently and in compliance with applicable law.

In any event, you can contact us in writing at the following addresses:  
  
NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.  
TechONE Tower1 11-12F,  
131, Bundangnaegok-ro, Bundang-gu,  
Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do,  
Republic of Korea.  
or  
  
WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.  
5700 Wilshire Blvd Suite 220,  
Los Angeles, CA 90036  
United States

#### 2\. Information We Collect

The following personal information is collected in connection with the Services:

##### Information you provide directly

When you use our Services, you may provide us with your personal information after being informed of the privacy information at the time of collection. For example:  
\- Contact information: When a user is considered a child in accordance with applicable law in user’s jurisdiction, we may need the user’s name and legal guardian’s e-mail address to obtain legal guardian’s consent depending on your jurisdiction. Moreover, when you participate in our events or promotions, we may ask for your name, phone number, address, email address and any other information required to deliver prizes and to respond to inquiries.  
\- Account information: When you create your own account and login to your account, we may need your date of birth, nickname, email address and password. Additionally, when you login to a third party account or to your profile with us, we may ask for information such as nickname or profile picture.  
\- Survey information: When you participate in our surveys or opinion polls, we may ask for your name, phone number, gender and any other information that can be reasonably required to conduct surveys or opinions and provide rewards.  
\- Image Information: When you choose to use toon filter, we may collect photos and gather information about the images, including identifying the objects and scenery that appear, as well as the presence and location of facial and body features and attributes within your photos. This information is not linked to your account and is soley used to enable the toon filter effect and detect inappropriate images. Please note that we do not use this information to identify specific individuals or for the purpose of training or improving our technology.  
\- Customer Care information: To provide responses when you contact our [Customer Care](https://webtoon.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/requests/new), we may collect any information you choose to provide, such as your requests or inquiries. When you communicate with our Customer Care staff or others, your communications will be transmitted through our systems through your email address.  
\- Identifiers such as a unique personal identifier (such as (i) device identifiers (e.g., cookies, beacons, pixel tags), (ii) mobile ad identifiers and similar technology, (iii) customer number, unique pseudonym, or user alias, (iv) telephone number and other forms of persistent or probabilistic identifiers), online identifier, Internet Protocol address other similar identifiers.

\[For Creators\]

When you use [CANVAS](https://www.webtoons.com/en/challenge) and/or AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAM, we may need to collect the following additional information:  
\- Creator Profile information: We may request information that you have voluntarily shared with the public through your Creator Profile page, including your profile picture, bio, social media links, website and more.  
\- We may request that your PayPal ID or Patreon ID be linked to the Service.  
\- We may request your uTip ID to provide reward or bonus.  
\- AD Revenue Payment Information: If you choose to provide your PayPal account, we may ask for additional information such as your Name (Legal Name/Business Alias), Full name/Business Name, Country, Residency, Address, Postal code, E-mail, Signature and Tax ID (or Social Security Number when applicable) for tax processing purposes.

\[For WEBTOON TRANSLATE Users\]

When you use [WEBTOON TRANSLATE](https://translate.webtoons.com/), we may need to collect the following additional information:  
\- Profile information: We may collect information that you have voluntarily shared with the public through your profile page, including your profile picture, nickname, user site URL, location and language of your choice.  
\- Team manager application information: If you apply as a team manager, we may request your “My Profile” URL, the language of your choice and other translating experiences.

##### Information collected through cookies and similar technologies

\- We and third parties may use cookies, web beacons, pixels, tags, and other tracking technologies (which we will refer to collectively as "cookies") to help us gather statistical information in order to improve your experience with the Services, save your preferences, and to provide you offers. These cookies may be used to track you across devices and websites over time. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies and session IDs, but you may be able to disable cookies by making the appropriate selection from your browser options or through the [Cookie Settings](https://www.webtoons.com/en/cookieSetting). Note that by doing so, the functionality of our Services may be limited.

To find out more on how we use the cookies collected, please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/cookiePolicy). To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://allaboutcookies.org/)

##### Information about your use of services

In addition to the information you provide, we will collect information about your use of our Services through software on your devices and by other means. We will collect:  
\- Service usage information: your interactions with the Services, dates and times of use of the Services and any Service usage information such as reading genre preferences, comments or likes, Coin and Free Passes balances, commercial information including purchase and transaction history, recent views, subscription history, download history, and event, promotion and/or contest participation;  
\- Information relating to the organization of contests and/or any promotional operations: date of participation, responses to the contests and nature of the prizes offered;  
\- Device and Log Information: Device and Log information such as device model, OS version, IP address, setting of devices, country information based on IP address, URL and network type; and  
\- Transaction /Purchase details: we do not collect or process any payment details concerning you (e.g., credit card details). Such information is only collected and processed through Apple’s App Store, Google Play Store, and PayPal. The only information that Apple, Google and PayPal may share with us is transaction and purchase details (e.g., transaction number, purchase history). Such information is only processed to validate the transactions.  
\- Inferences: We may draw inferences of your interests, preferences, and gender cohort based on information about your interactions with our Services or advertising partners.

##### Information collected through 3rd Party Analytics

\- Through certain Services, we may collect personal information about your online activities on websites and connected devices over time and across third-party websites, devices, apps and other online features and services. We may use third-party analytics services on the Services. The information we obtain may be disclosed to or collected directly by these providers and other relevant third parties who use the information, for example, to evaluate use of the Services or help administer the Services.

#### 3\. How We Use the Information We Collect

We may use the information collected above for the following purposes:

\[For Users and Creators\]

\- Identify and authenticate you and administer your account  
\- Provide a Service or feature you request, such as to respond to your request, questions and instructions made through the Services;  
\- Conduct surveys and analyses necessary for improving the Service;  
\- Send you information and prizes for campaigns and events;  
\- Processing payment and billing when a user purchases a product or uses a Service that is not free;  
\- Provide you with tailored functions such as recommendation based on your age and/or service usage information such as your most visited webpages, and additional content tailored to your interests via the Interest tab;  
\- Provide you with ads which may include personalized or targeted (or interest-based) ads;  
\- Send you communications via email or in-product notifications (e.g., pop-up notification, push notification) in relation to our Services as controlled by your communication preferences;  
\- Monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities in connection with our products and services;  
\- Create de-identified, anonymized or aggregated information;  
\- Deliver and protect Digital Content;  
\- Verify age and provide age-appropriate content and experiences;  
\- Ensure the information security of our Services;  
\- Protect against, identify and prevent fraud and other criminal activity, claims and other liabilities;  
\- Generate statistical data pertaining to usage of the Services;  
\- Ensure and monitor the effectiveness and availability of the services to improve performance of the website and the application;  
\- Comply with and enforce applicable law requirements, our statutory obligations (e.g., tax laws), relevant industry standards and our policies, including this Privacy Policy;  
\- Validate transaction and prevent fraud and abuse;  
\- Respond to your inquiries and send users important notifications when necessary; and  
\- Carry out any other purpose described to you at the time the information was collected

\[For Creators using CANVAS and/or AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAM\]

In addition to the above purposes, we may use the information collected on creators using [CANVAS](https://www.webtoons.com/en/challenge) and/or [AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAM](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/adRevenueSharingPolicy) for the following additional purposes:  
\- Provide rewards, bonus or deliver prizes to survey participants, contest entrants or winners;  
\- Verify your identity to comply with applicable federal laws;  
\- Provide AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAM to users;  
\- Send emails relevant to your work or usage, as controlled by your email preference;  
\- Reply to your questions;  
\- Understand how you use the Service and create better AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAMs;  
\- Generate statistical data pertaining to usage of the Services;  
\- Conduct research and development to improve AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAM and develop future products;  
\- Comply with and enforce applicable law requirements, our statutory obligations (e.g., tax laws), relevant industry standards and our policies, including this Privacy Policy; and  
\- Prevent fraud and abuse of AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAM and prevent other criminal activity, claims and liabilities.

#### 4\. Information Sharing

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. and WEBTOON Entertainment Inc. share information as joint controllers of your personal information whenever necessary to provide Services efficiently and in compliance with applicable law. We disclose or share personal information about you through the Services as described in the following:  
\- **Publicly Available Information**. Information that you have voluntarily registered to be shared with the public can be seen by anyone, including those who do not have an account. This may include your nickname, profile picture, short bio, social media links, website, other information on your public profile, and any information or content you share with a public audience.  
\- **Service Providers**. We may disclose your information to companies that provide Services on behalf of us, such as companies that help us develop and operate systems for the Service with customer contact centers, as well as customer care activities, advertising (including customized advertising on our websites, third-party websites, or online platforms), conducting customer satisfaction surveys, billing or that send emails on our behalf. These entities are limited by contractual provisions in their ability to use your information for purposes other than providing Services for us.  
Acting as service providers in accordance with legal regulations, such suppliers may have access to your personal information in order to provide the services and/or comply with the obligations arising from the legal relationships maintained between the aforementioned third parties and us. In any case, we have signed the corresponding confidentiality and data protection agreements with those service providers, in full compliance with the provisions of current legislation on data protection.  
\- **Payment Partners**. Payment and purchase information is collected and processed by payment partners for payment processing and anti-fraud purposes.  
\- **Advertising Partners**. We may share your information to deliver more relevant advertising to you and help measure the effectiveness of ads.  
\- **Marketing Partners**. We may share your information to enable you participate in our promotions, promote our Services in other platforms, and measure the effectiveness of our marketing activities.  
\- **Our Affiliated Companies**. We may share your personal information with our subsidiaries for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.  
\- **Other Parties When Required by Law or as Necessary to Protect Our Services**. There may be instances when we disclose your information to other parties:  
\- to comply with the law or respond to compulsory legal process (such as a search warrant or other court order);  
\- to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our Services; and  
\- to protect our rights, property, or safety, or, in compliance with data protection laws, any of our respective affiliates, business partners, or customers.  
\- **Other Parties in Connection with Transactions**. We may disclose your information to a third party as part of an actual or planned merger or transfer, acquisition or sale, or in the event of a bankruptcy.  
\- **Other Parties with Your Consent or on Your Request**. In addition to the disclosures described in this Privacy Policy, we may share information about you with third parties when you separately consent to or request such sharing.  
\- **Links to Other Websites, Devices, Apps and Features**. The Service may provide the ability to connect to other websites, devices, apps and other features, which may operate independently from us and may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review. To the extent any linked website, device, app or other feature is not owned or controlled by us, we are not responsible for its content, use or privacy practices.

#### 5\. Retention of Personal Information

We take appropriate steps to ensure that we process and retain information about you based on the following logic:  
\- at the minimum duration for which the information is used to provide you with a service;  
\- as required under law, a contract, or with regard to our statutory obligations (e.g., tax laws); or  
\- only for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected, is processed, or longer if required under any contract, by applicable law, or, in anonymized form, for statistical purposes, subject to appropriate safeguards.  
  
Thus, we will only keep your personal data for as long as we need it for the purposes for which we collect them and to comply with legal, financial, business or reporting requirements. When we no longer need the personal information, we will securely delete or destroy it.  
We will store the collected data even thereafter, until the expiration of any legal liability arising therefrom.

#### 6\. Your Rights

Your personal information belongs to you. Depending on the jurisdiction in which you reside, you can ask us to provide details about what we’ve collected, and you can ask us to correct any inaccuracies. The details of your rights are as follows:

**Your right of access**: you have the right to ask us whether or not we are using or storing your personal information. You can also ask us for copies of your personal information.  
**Your right to rectification**: you have the right to ask us to rectify information you think is inaccurate. You also have the right to complete information you consider is incomplete.  
**Your right to erasure**: you have the right to ask us to erase your personal information in the following circumstances: (i) we no longer need your personal information, (ii) you initially consented to the use of your personal information, but have now withdrawn your consent, (iii) you have objected to the use of your personal information and your interests outweigh those of our company, (iv) we have collected or used your personal information unlawfully, and/or (v) we have a legal obligation to erase your personal information.  
**Your right to restrict processing**: you have the right to ask us to restrict the processing of your personal information in the following circumstances: (i) you have challenged the accuracy of your personal information, (ii) you have objected to the use of your personal information, (iii) we processed your personal information unlawfully without you wishing to delete it, and/or (iv) we no longer need your personal information but you wish us to keep it in order to defend or exercise legal claims.  
**Your right to object to processing**: you have the right to object to the processing of your personal information if we are using your personal information for (i) a task carried out in the public interest, (ii) our legitimate interests, (iii) scientific or historical research or statistical purposes, or (iv) direct marketing.  
**Your right to data portability**: this right applies to personal information you have provided to us and where the processing is automated, based on your consent or made under a contract. You have the right to ask us, if technically feasible, to transfer your personal information to another organisation or directly provide it to you in a way accessible and machine readable.  
**You also have the right to withdraw consent**: at any time where the processing is based on your consent, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before such withdrawal.  
**You have the right to lodge a complaint before a supervisory authority**: you can lodge a complaint with the relevant supervisory authority if you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes applicable law.

#### 7\. Exercising Your Rights and Your Choices

If you want to exercise the above rights or if you would like to submit your request, please contact us as specified in the [Contact Us](#pp_10_en) section (section 10 of this Privacy Policy). However, if permitted by law, we may charge you a small fee for providing you with this ability. Subject to applicable law, we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or for which access is not otherwise required by local law.

You may access or correct your personal information registered with us at any time via the “Account” or “Creator Profile” page.

You may ask us to delete your personal information by deleting your account at any time. If you have any series published on CANVAS, you must delete them first to delete your account. Once you delete your account, your account profile and subscription history will be deleted permanently and become unrecoverable. Any tax information submitted to us will be maintained for a period of time, as required by financial laws and regulations.

If you would like to change your preference regarding our communications (including marketing communications), you can change your communication preferences from “Account” page or “Settings” page. You can also unsubscribe from our email marketing communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link on the bottom of the email.

You can manage the use of optional cookies by clicking on the “Cookie Settings” solution displayed when you open the application/visit the website and at any time through the Cookie Settings. To find out more on how we use the cookies collected, please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/cookiePolicy). You can also restrict or disable certain types of cookies by visiting [https://www.allaboutcookies.org/](https://allaboutcookies.org/) or [https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1).

#### 8\. How We Protect Personal Information

We take protection of your information seriously and maintain safeguards designed to protect the information we collect in connection with the Services. The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your information as it is transmitted to us. To the extent permitted under applicable law, we assume no liability or responsibility for disclosure of your information due to errors in transmission, unauthorized access by third-parties or other causes beyond our control.

You play an important role in keeping your information secure. You should not share your username or password for your account with anyone. If you have reason to believe that your account is no longer secure, please contact us immediately.

#### 9\. Children’s Personal Information

The Services are designed for a general audience. If the consent of the parent (or legal guardian) is required to process the child's personal information pursuant to the applicable law, we will process such information upon obtaining consent of the parent (or legal guardian) in accordance with the legally required process.

#### 10\. Contact Us

\- If you have any questions, concerns or inquiries concerning the Policies for handling personal information, you may send them to our personal information management department at: [Customer Care](https://webtoon.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/requests/new).  
\- You can contact us by sending an email to our Data Protection Officer (DPO) at the following address: [dpo@webtoonscorp.com](mailto:dpo@webtoonscorp.com)  
\- In any event, you can contact us in writing at the following addresses.  
  
NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.  
TechONE Tower1 11-12F,  
131, Bundangnaegok-ro, Bundang-gu,  
Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do,  
Republic of Korea.  
  
As NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. and WEBTOON Entertainment Inc. will take joint action whenever necessary to comply with your rights, requests or complaints, you can also contact us at WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.:  
  
WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.  
5700 Wilshire Blvd Suite 220,  
Los Angeles, CA 90036  
United States

#### 11\. Links to Other Websites

You may identify hyperlinks to access the websites of other organisations on our websites or in the content we provide to you (e.g., promotional email or events). Please note that this privacy policy does not cover how other companies will process your personal information. We recommend you to read the privacy policies applicable to such other websites.

#### 12\. Updates to Our Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy may be updated to reflect changes in our personal information practices with respect to the Service, or changes in the applicable law. We will post a notice on our Service to notify you in advance of material changes to our Privacy Policy and indicate at the top of the notice when it was most recently updated.  
  
This Privacy Policy is effective from – Marh 26, 2024 (effective immediately for new users).

#### 13\. Regional Privacy Disclosures

##### 13.1 For U.S. Residents

This section supplements the WEBTOON Privacy Policy and applies solely to U.S. residents.  
  
**Information we process**  
\- We may request date of birth, to verify your ability to access certain features of the Services and to tailor content and advertisements to you.  
\- When a child is under 13 years of age, we collect the child's name and parent's e-mail address from the child that are necessary to provide any necessary notice and to obtain parental consent.  
  
**Children’s Personal Information**  
Users under the age of 13 are not the primary audience for our service as it relates to the COPPA compliance. We may ask you to provide age-related information in order to help us comply with data protection laws. In particular, we will request your date of birth to determine whether or not you are allowed to benefit from the services or if we have to obtain verifiable parental consent from your parent or relevant holder of parental responsibility before allowing you to access and/or benefit from the services. If parental consent from user’s parents or legal guardian is necessary, we will obtain such consent before processing personal information of children. To read about our privacy policy for children, please see the [Children’s Privacy Policy](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/childrensPrivacyPolicy).

##### 13.2 For Consumers Residing in Certain U.S. States

This section supplements the [WEBTOON Privacy Policy](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/privacyPolicy) and applies to consumers who reside in jurisdictions where there is a privacy statute (excluding WEBTOON ENTERTAINMENT Inc. applicants and personnel).  
  
**A. Collection, Use, and Disclosure of Personal Information**  
  
**(1) Categories of Personal Information We Collect**: We may have collected the following categories of personal information about you in the last 12 months:  
\- Identifiers such as name, citizenship, residence address, unique personal identifier (such as a device identifier; cookies, beacons, pixel tags, mobile ad identifiers and similar technology, customer number, unique pseudonym, or user alias, telephone number and other forms of persistent or probabilistic identifiers), online identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address, account name, and other similar identifiers (including date of birth, contact information, account information, identifiers, survey information, customer care information, Creator Profile information, PayPal ID, Patreon ID, uTip ID, AD Revenue Payment Information, WEBTOON TRANSLATE Profile and team manager application information stipulated in section 2 above);  
\- Other identifying information, such as social security number, tax ID, tax form;  
\- Commercial information, including records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, and other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies (including transaction and purchase details stipulated in section 2 above);  
\- Internet and other electronic network activity information, including, but not limited to information regarding your interaction with websites, applications or advertisements (including information about your use of Services and information collected through 3rd Party Analytics stipulated in section 2 above);  
\- Sensory information including electronic, visual, or similar information;  
\- Biometric identifiers and biometric information: when you choose to use toon filter, we may collect biometric identifiers and biometric information as defined under certain U.S. state laws, such as image of face and features and attributes of your face and body to enable filter effect and detect inappropriate images. We do not use this information to identify specific individuals or for the purpose of training or improving our technology. Where required by law, we will seek your consent from you prior to any such collection; and  
\- Inferences drawn from any of the above information, including information regarding your interactions with our Services and preferences, information about your activities and interactions with our advertising partners, and gender cohort based on your interactions and preferences.  
  
**(2) Sensitive Personal Information**: Depending on the state in which you reside, we may collect some sensitive personal information about you when you use the Services, such as social security number for tax purposes.  
  
**(3) Categories of Sources of Personal Information**: We may have collected personal information about you from the following categories of sources:  
\- From you or your devices, for example, through your use of the Services;  
\- Our affiliated companies which provide services on our behalf, such as customer support and payment processing;  
\- Vendors who provide Services on our behalf;  
\- Advertising networks;  
\- Data analytics providers;  
\- Payment partners; and  
\- Social media networks.  
  
**(4) Business & Commercial Purposes for Collecting Personal Information**: To understand the purposes for which we collect personal information, please review [3\. How We Use the Information We Collect](#pp_3_en) of this [Privacy Policy](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/privacyPolicy).  
  
**(5) Categories of Third Parties with Whom Personal Information is Disclosed**: In the preceding 12 months, we have disclosed your personal information with the following categories of third parties:  
\- Our affiliates, subsidiaries and business partners;  
\- Vendors who provide services on our behalf;  
\- Payment partners;  
\- Social networks;  
\- Other users or creators;  
\- Professional services organizations, such as auditors and law firms;  
\- Ad networks, marketing partners, analytics providers; and  
\- Other third parties when you separately consent to or request such sharing.  
  
We may also disclose your personal information with the following categories of third parties:  
\- A third party as part of an actual or planned merger or transfer, acquisition or sale, or in the event of a bankruptcy;  
\- Government entities, including law enforcement as required by law.  
  
**(6) Categories of Personal Information Disclosed for a Business Purpose**: In the preceding 12 months, we may have disclosed the following categories of personal information about you for a business purpose: identifiers, other identifying information (e.g., social security number), financial information, commercial information, internet and other electronic network activity information, sensory information, and inferences.  
  
**(7) Categories of Personal Information Sold & Third Parties**: We have sold the following categories of personal information about you to the following categories of third parties:  
\- Advertising/marketing cookies and similar information to advertising partners in order to show you targeted advertisement based on your interactions with our Services;  
\- Identifiers such as a unique personal identifier (such as a device identifier; cookies, beacons, pixel tags, mobile ad identifiers and similar technology; other forms of persistent or probabilistic identifiers), online identifier, and internet protocol address, which we share with our service providers, advertising partners, and other vendors to provide the Services;  
\- Internet and other electronic network activity information, including, but not limited to, browsing history, search history, and information regarding your interaction with websites, applications or advertisements, which we share with our service providers, advertising partners, and other vendors to provide the Services; and  
\- Inferences, which we share with our service providers, advertising partners, and other vendors to provide the Services.  
  
We do have actual knowledge that we have sold personal information of consumers under the age of 16 only with consent.  
  
**(8) Categories of Personal Information Shared for Targeted Advertising & Third Parties**: The categories of personal information that we have shared for targeting advertising include:  
\- Advertising/marketing cookies and similar information to advertising partners in order to show you targeted advertisement based on your interactions with our Services;  
\- Identifiers such as a unique personal identifier (such as a device identifier; cookies, beacons, pixel tags, mobile ad identifiers and similar technology; other forms of persistent or probabilistic identifiers), online identifier, and internet protocol address, which we share with our service providers, advertising partners, and other vendors to provide the Services;  
\- Internet and other electronic network activity information, including, but not limited to, browsing history, search history, and information regarding your interaction with websites, applications or advertisements, which we share with our service providers, advertising partners, and other vendors to provide the Services; and  
\- Inferences, which we share with our service providers, advertising partners, and other vendors to provide the Services.  
  
We do have actual knowledge that we have shared personal information of consumers under the age of 16 only with consent.  
  
**B. Consumer Rights**  
  
Depending on where you reside, and subject to applicable law and exceptions, you may be entitled to the following rights with respect to your personal information:  
  
\- **Right to Know**: Subject to applicable exceptions, you may have the right to request that we disclose personal information that we have collected, sold, or shared about you in the past 12 months, including:  
o the categories and specific pieces of personal information we have collected about you; o the categories of sources from which we collected the personal information; o the categories of personal information about you that we sold or disclosed for a business purpose, and the categories of third parties to whom we sold or disclosed that information for a business purpose; and o the business or commercial purpose for which we collected or sold the personal information.  
\- **Right to Data Portability**: You may have the right to request that personal information that has been collected and maintained about you be transferred to you via a secure method in a commonly used electronic format that enables you to have complete access to and full enjoyment of your data, subject to applicable law and exceptions, including, but not limited to, the capacity to save, edit, and transfer the personal information to any other person or platform at your discretion.  
  
\- **Right to Correct**: Subject to applicable law and exceptions, you may have the right to correct or modify inaccurate personal information that we may have collected about you.  
  
\- **Right to Delete**: You may have the right to request that we delete the personal information we have collected from you, subject to applicable law and exceptions.  
  
\- **Sale of Personal Information & Targeted Advertising**: Depending on the state in which you reside, you may have the right to opt out of the sale of your personal information and targeted advertising. To opt out, please click ["Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information"](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/dnsmpi) or click the link on our homepage.  
  
\- **Non-Discrimination**: We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights and choices, although some of the functionality and features available on the Service may change or no longer be available to you.  
  
\- **Other California Rights**:  
o **Shine the Light**: California residents are entitled once a year, free of charge, to request and obtain certain information regarding our disclosure, if any, of certain categories of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. We do not share personal information with third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. o **Do Not Track**: Some web browsers transmit “do-not-track” signals to websites. Because of differences in how web browsers incorporate and activate this feature, it is not always clear whether users intend for these signals to be transmitted, or whether they even are aware of them. We currently do not take action in response to these signals.  
To submit an access, deletion, correction, or portability request, [click here](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/dnsmpi) or contact us as specified in the [Contact Us](#pp_10_en) section of this Privacy Policy. We may require that you provide us with your e-mail address. When we receive your request, we will review the information that you provide and attempt to use it to verify your identity by comparing it against the information we have on file. You may also have an authorized agent submit a request on your behalf through this process. When we receive such a request, we will process the request, consistent with our standard process for verifying consumer requests. In addition, we may request information to demonstrate the agent’s authority to act on your behalf. You may have the right to appeal a denial of your consumer rights request by [Customer Care](https://webtoon.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/requests/new) or email contact ([dpo@webtoonscorp.com](mailto:dpo@webtoonscorp.com)).  
  
As noted above, we do not engage in profiling to make decisions that result in a legal or similarly significant effect based solely on automated processing of your personal information. All decision-making processes related to the processing purposes described above are carried out with human intervention.  
  
Although some of the information that we may collect could be considered sensitive information under certain U.S. state privacy laws, we only use and disclose sensitive information for a subset of the purposes described above. For example, we may collect and process SSNs and information of citizenship for tax purposes.  
  
You may access or correct your personal information registered with us at any time via the “Account” or “Creator Profile” page.  
  
You may ask us to delete your personal information by deleting your account at any time. If you have any series published on CANVAS, you must delete them first to delete your account. Once you delete your account, your account profile and subscription history will be deleted permanently and become unrecoverable. Any tax information submitted to us will be maintained for a period of time, as required by financial laws and regulations.  
  
If you would like to change your preference regarding our communications (including marketing communications), you can change your communication preferences from “Account” page or “Settings” page. You can also unsubscribe from our email marketing communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link on the bottom of the email.  
  
If you do not want us to use your personal information such as account information and inferences about you based on your activity to show you personalized ads on WEBTOON, you can turn off personalized ads in Ads Settings.  
  
You can manage the use of optional cookies by clicking on the “Cookie Settings” solution displayed when you open the application/visit the website and at any time through the Cookie Settings. To find out more on how we use the cookies collected, please refer to our Cookie Policy. You can also restrict or disable certain types of cookies by visiting [https://www.allaboutcookies.org/](https://allaboutcookies.org/) or [https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1).  
  
**C. Data Retention**  
  
We take appropriate steps to ensure that we process and retain information about you based on the following logic:  
\- at the minimum duration for which the information is used to provide you with a service;  
\- as required under law, a contract, or with regard to our statutory obligations (e.g., tax laws); or  
\- only for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected, is processed, or longer if required under any contract, by applicable law, or, in anonymized form, for statistical purposes, subject to appropriate safeguards.  
  
Thus, we will only keep your personal information for as long as we need it for the purposes for which we collect them and to comply with legal, financial, business or reporting requirements. When we no longer need the personal information, we will securely delete or destroy it.  
We will store the collected data even thereafter, until the expiration of any legal liability arising therefrom.  
  
**D. Other Topics**  
  
**Contact Information**: You can contact us by sending an email to the following address: [dpo@webtoonscorp.com](mailto:dpo@webtoonscorp.com)

### WEBTOON™ – PRINCIPAUX ÉLÉMENTS DE LA POLITIQUE DE PROTECTION DES DONNÉES POUR LA FRANCE

Mise à jour le 26 Mars 2024.

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. (y compris ses filiales, ci-après dénommées ensemble « nous » ou « notre ») attache de l’importance à la protection de votre vie privée. La présente Politique de protection des données s’applique aux données à caractère personnel collectées via l’application et/ou le site web WEBTOON TRANSLATE et CANVAS (désignés ensemble comme les « **Services** »).

#### VUE D’ENSEMBLE DE LA POLITIQUE DE PROTECTION DES DONNÉES

La présente Politique de protection des données décrit les types de données à caractère personnel que nous traitons via nos Services, la manière dont nous pouvons utiliser ces données, les entités avec lesquelles nous pouvons les partager ainsi que les possibilités dont vous disposez quant à l’utilisation de ces données et à l’exercice de vos droits. Elle décrit également les mesures que nous prenons pour sécuriser les données et vous indique comment nous contacter pour toute question relative à nos pratiques de protection des données. Vous trouverez ci-dessous un résumé des principaux messages de notre Politique de protection des données. Pour plus d’informations sur la manière dont nous traitons vos données, veuillez cliquer sur les titres ou poursuivre la lecture ci-dessous

[8\. Comment nous protégeons les données à caractère personnel](#pp_8_fr)  
[12\. Mises à jour de notre Politique de protection des données](#pp_12_fr)  

### POLITIQUE DE PROTECTION DES DONNÉES DE WEBTOON™ POUR LA FRANCE

#### 1\. Responsables du traitement

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. et WEBTOON Entertainment Inc. sont responsables conjointement du traitement des données à caractère personnel. Ils partagent à ce titre des données afin de garantir une fourniture efficace de leurs Services et ce, dans le respect des lois applicables.

Pour toute demande, vous pouvez nous contacter par écrit aux coordonnées suivantes :  
  
NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.  
TechONE Tower1 11-12F,  
131, Bundangnaegok-ro, Bundang-gu,  
Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do,  
République de Corée  
ou  
  
WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.  
5700 Wilshire Blvd Suite 220,  
Los Angeles, CA 90036  
USA

#### 2\. Données que nous collectons

Les données à caractère personnel suivantes sont collectées dans le cadre des Services :

##### Données que vous nous communiquez directement

Lorsque vous utilisez nos Services, vous pouvez nous fournir des renseignements personnels comprenant notamment les informations suivantes:  
\- Coordonnées : dans l’hypothèse où l’un de nos utilisateurs serait considéré comme mineur au titre des lois applicables sur le territoire dans lequel il relève, nous pouvons requérir la communication du nom de l’utilisateur et de l’adresse électronique de son représentant légal afin d’obtenir le consentement de ce dernier, en fonction du territoire où vous vous trouvez. Par ailleurs, au titre de votre participation à nos événements ou promotions, nous pouvons être amenés à vous demander votre nom, numéro de téléphone, adresse, et adresse électronique ainsi que toute autre information nécessaire à la remise de prix et à la réponse aux sollicitations.  
\- Données de compte : lorsque vous créez votre propre compte et que vous vous connectez à votre compte, nous pouvons avoir besoin de votre date de naissance, pseudonyme/identifiant, adresse électronique et de votre mot de passe. De plus, lorsque vous vous connectez à votre profil ou à un compte tiers, nous pouvons vous demander des informations telles que votre pseudonyme ou votre photo de profil.  
\- Données liées à des enquêtes : lorsque vous participez à nos enquêtes ou sondages d’opinion, nous pouvons demander votre nom, votre numéro de téléphone, votre sexe et toute autre information pouvant raisonnablement être requise à ces fins, ou encore dans le but d’accorder des récompenses.  
\- Information de l’image : Lorsque vous utilisez toon filter, nous pouvons collecter vos photos et assembler les informations sur les images, ce qui inclut l’identification des objets et du paysage apparaissant dans celles-ci, ainsi que la présence et l’emplacement des traits et attributs facials et corporels dans ces photos. Ces informations ne sont pas liées à votre compte et ne sont utilisées que pour les effets de toon filter et pour détecter les images inappropriées. Veuillez prendre en note que nous n’utilisons pas ces informations pour identifier des individus spécifiques ou pour des objectifs d’apprentissage ou pour l’amélioration de notre technologie.  
\- Données liées au Service Client : pour être en mesure de vous répondre lorsque vous contactez notre [Service Client](https://contact-cc.line.me/webtoon/fr/), nous pouvons collecter toutes les informations que vous décidez de nous divulguer, telles que vos demandes ou questions. Lorsque vous communiquez avec les employés de notre Service Client ou autres, vos communications seront transmises dans nos systèmes via votre adresse électronique.  
\- Identifiants, tels que l’identifiant personnel unique (en ce compris (i) les identifiants d’appareil (ex : cookies, balises, pixels invisibles), (ii) identifiants d’annonces publicitaires mobiles et technologies similaires, (iii) numéro de client, pseudonyme unique ou alias d’utilisateur, (iv) numéro de téléphone et toutes autres formes d’identifiants persistants ou probables), identifiant en ligne, adresse Internet Protocol ou autres identifiants similaires.

\[Pour les Créateurs\]

Si vous utilisez [CANVAS](https://www.webtoons.com/fr/challenge) et/ou le PROGRAMME DE PARTAGE DES REVENUS PUBLICITAIRES, nous pouvons avoir besoin de collecter les données complémentaires suivantes :  
\- Données de profil Créateur : nous pouvons demander des données que vous avez volontairement partagées avec le public via votre page de Profil de créateur, notamment votre photo de profil, votre biographie, vos liens de réseaux sociaux, votre site web et plus.  
\- Nous pouvons demander que votre identifiant PayPal ou votre identifiant Patreon soient associés au Service.  
\- Nous pouvons demander votre identifiant uTip pour vous accorder des récompenses ou primes.  
\- Informations de paiement des revenus publicitaires : si vous décidez de nous communiquer votre compte PayPal, nous pouvons demander des informations complémentaires telles que votre Nom complet / Dénomination sociale, Raison d’être, Pays, Domicile, Adresse, Code postal, Adresse électronique, Signature et Numéro fiscal (ou Numéro de sécurité sociale si applicable) à des fins de traitement fiscal.  

\[Pour les utilisateurs de WEBTOON TRANSLATE\]

Lorsque vous utilisez [WEBTOON TRANSLATE](https://translate.webtoons.com/), nous pouvons collecter les données complémentaires suivantes :  
\- Données de profil : nous pouvons collecter des données que vous avez volontairement partagées avec le public via votre page de profil, notamment votre photo de profil, pseudonyme, URL du site de l’utilisateur, localisation et la langue choisie.  
\- Données relatives aux candidatures au poste de chef d’équipe : si vous postulez comme chef d’équipe, nous pouvons demander votre URL « Mon Profil », la langue que vous avez choisie et vos autres expériences en traduction.

##### Données collectées via des cookies et autres technologies similaires

\- Des tiers, ainsi que nous même, pouvons utiliser des cookies, balises web, pixels, tags et autres technologies de traçage (que nous désignerons ensemble sous le terme de « cookies ») pour nous aider à collecter des données statistiques dans le but d’améliorer votre expérience lors de l’utilisation des Services, d’enregistrer vos préférences et de vous envoyer des offres. Ces cookies peuvent être utilisés pour suivre votre activité sur différents appareils et sites web dans le temps. La plupart des navigateurs web acceptent automatiquement les cookies et identifiants de session, mais vous pouvez éventuellement désactiver les cookies en sélectionnant les options appropriées dans votre navigateur, ou via nos [paramétrage des cookies](https://www.webtoons.com/fr/cookieSetting). Notez que dans ce cas, la fonctionnalité de nos Services pourra être restreinte.

Pour en savoir plus sur la manière dont nous utilisons les cookies que nous collectons, veuillez consulter notre [Politique de Cookies](https://www.webtoons.com/fr/terms/cookiePolicy). Pour en savoir plus sur les cookies, notamment pour savoir quels cookies ont été déposés, consultez [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/) ou [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://allaboutcookies.org/).

##### Données sur votre utilisation des services

En plus des données que vous nous communiquez, nous collectons des données sur votre utilisation de nos Services par le biais d’un logiciel sur vos appareils et par tout autres moyens. Nous collectons les données suivantes :  
\- Données sur l’utilisation des Services : vos interactions avec les Services, les dates et heures de votre utilisation des Services ainsi que toute information sur l’utilisation des Services, notamment sur vos préférences de genre de lecture, vos commentaires et « likes », vos soldes de « Coins » et Free Pass, ainsi que toutes données commerciales y compris l’historique des achats et transactions, vues récentes, des abonnements et téléchargements et de participation à des événements, promotions et/ou concours ;  
\- Données sur l’organisation de concours et/ou opérations promotionnelles : date de participation, réponses aux concours et nature des prix offerts ;  
\- Sur les appareils et les connexions : les données sur les appareils et les connexions et, notamment sur le modèle d’appareil, version du système d’exploitation, adresse IP, configuration de l’appareil, données sur le pays basées sur l’adresse IP, URL et type de réseau et ;  
\- Données sur les Transactions/Achats : nous ne collectons ni ne traitons aucune information de paiement vous concernant (données de carte de crédit par exemple). Ces données sont uniquement collectées et traitées par l’App Store d’Apple, le Google PlayStore et PayPal. Les seules données qu’Apple, Google et PayPal peuvent partager avec nous sont les données sur les transactions et les achats (tels que le numéro de transaction, l’historique des achats). Ces données sont uniquement traitées dans le but de valider les transactions.  
\- Inférences : Nous pouvons déduire vos intérêts, préférences, et votre genre en se basant de l'information de vos interactions avec nos Services ou nos partenaires publicitaires.

##### Données collectées par des services d'analyse tiers

\- À travers certains Services, nous pouvons collecter des données à caractère personnel portant sur vos activités sur des sites web et appareils connectés au cours du temps et sur des sites web, appareils, applications et autres fonctions et services en ligne tiers. Nous pouvons utiliser des services d’analyse tiers dans le cadre des Services. Les données que nous obtenons peuvent être divulguées directement à ces prestataires et aux tiers concernés, ou collectées directement par ces parties, qui les utiliseront par exemple pour évaluer l’utilisation des Services ou faciliter la gestion des Services.

#### 3\. Comment nous utilisons les données que nous collectons

##### Nous pouvons utiliser les données collectées ci-dessus aux fins suivantes :

\[Pour les Utilisateurs et Créateurs\]

\- Vous identifier et vous authentifier et gérer votre compte  
\- Fournir un Service ou une fonction que vous demandez, notamment pour répondre à vos demandes, questions et instructions introduites via les Services ;  
\- Réaliser les enquêtes et analyses requises pour l’amélioration du Service ;  
\- Vous envoyer des données et prix dans le cadre des campagnes et événements ;  
\- Traiter le paiement et la facturation lorsqu’un utilisateur achète un produit ou utilise un Service qui n’est pas gratuit ;  
\- Vous fournir des fonctions adaptées, telle que la recommandation basée sur votre âge et/ou sur les informations de votre utilisation telles que les pages web les plus visitées, et des contenus supplémentaires adaptés à vos intérêts reconnus par le tab Intérêt.  
\- Vous fournir des publicités qui peuvent inclure des publicités personnalisées ou ciblées (ou basées sur les intérêts).  
\- Vous envoyer des communications par email ou des notifications au sein d’un produit (par exemple notification pop-up, notification push) en lien avec nos Services, conformément aux préférences de communication que vous définissez ;  
\- Suivre et analyser les tendances, l’utilisation et les activités en lien avec nos produits et services ;  
\- Créer des données non identifiées, anonymisées ou agrégées ;  
\- Fournir et protéger un Contenu numérique ;  
\- Vérifier votre âge et fournir une expérience adaptée à votre âge ;  
\- Assurer la sécurité des données dans le cadre de nos Services ;  
\- Identifier, prévenir et se prémunir contre les fraudes et autres activités criminelles, les demandes de réparation et autres cas d’engagement de responsabilité ;  
\- Générer des données statistiques sur l’utilisation des Services ;  
\- Assurer et surveiller l’efficacité et la disponibilité des services afin d’améliorer les performances du site web et de l’application ;  
\- Respecter et faire appliquer les exigences légales applicables, nos obligations légales (notamment en matière fiscale), les normes applicables du secteur ainsi que nos politiques, y compris la présente Politique de protection des données ;  
\- Valider les transactions et prévenir la fraude et l’utilisation abusive ;  
\- Répondre à vos demandes d'information et envoyer aux utilisateurs des notifications importantes lorsque nécessaire, et  
\- Effectuer toute autre activité qui vous a été décrite au moment où les données ont été collectées.

\[Pour les Créateurs utilisant CANVAS et/ou le PROGRAMME DE PARTAGE DES REVENUS PUBLICITAIRES\]

En plus des fins décrites ci-dessus, nous pouvons utiliser les données collectées sur les créateurs utilisant [CANVAS](https://www.webtoons.com/fr/challenge) et/ou [le PROGRAMME DE PARTAGE DES REVENUS PUBLICITAIRES](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/adRevenueSharingPolicy) aux fins suivantes :  
\- Fournir des récompenses ou primes ou remettre des prix aux participants à une enquête ou aux participants ou vainqueurs d’un concours ;  
\- Vérifier votre identité afin de respecter les lois fédérales applicables ;  
\- Mettre le PROGRAMME DE PARTAGE DES REVENUS PUBLICITAIRES à disposition des utilisateurs ;  
\- Envoyer des emails portant sur votre travail ou votre utilisation, conformément aux préférences d’email que vous avez définies ;  
\- Répondre à vos questions ;  
\- Comprendre comment vous utilisez le Service et créer de meilleurs PROGRAMMES DE PARTAGE DES REVENUS PUBLICITAIRES ;  
\- Générer des données statistiques portant sur l’utilisation de nos Services ;  
\- Effectuer des activités de recherche et développement pour améliorer notre PROGRAMME DE PARTAGE DES REVENUS PUBLICITAIRES et développer de futurs produits ;  
\- Respecter et faire appliquer les exigences légales applicables, nos obligations légales (notamment en matière fiscale), les normes applicables du secteur ainsi que nos politiques, y compris la présente Politique de protection des données, et  
\- Prévenir la fraude et l’utilisation abusive du PROGRAMME DE PARTAGE DES REVENUS PUBLICITAIRES et se prémunir de toutes autres activités criminelles, demandes de réparation et autres cas d’engagement de responsabilité.

#### 4\. Partage de données

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. et WEBTOON Entertainment Inc. partagent des données afin de fournir les Services efficacement et dans le respect des lois applicables. Nous divulguons ou partageons des données à caractère personnel vous concernant via les Services comme décrit dans les sections qui suivent :  
\- **Données accessibles au public**. Les données pour lesquelles vous avez volontairement accepté qu’elles soient partagées avec le public, peuvent être consultées par toute personne, y compris celles ne disposant pas d’un compte. Ces données peuvent inclure votre pseudonyme, votre photo de profil, votre brève biographie, vos liens vers des réseaux sociaux, votre site web, d'autres données présentes sur votre profil public ainsi que toute information ou contenu que vous partagez avec le public.  
\- **Prestataires de services**. Nous pouvons divulguer vos données à des sociétés fournissant des Services pour notre compte, comme des sociétés qui nous aident à développer et à exploiter des systèmes pour le Service avec des centres de contact client, ainsi que des activités de service client et de la publicité (y compris de la publicité personnalisée sur nos sites web, des sites web tiers ou des plateformes en ligne), à réaliser des enquêtes de satisfaction client et des opérations de facturation ou à envoyer des emails pour notre compte. Ces entités sont contractuellement limitées dans leur capacité à utiliser vos données à des fins autres que la fourniture de Services à notre demande.  
En agissant en tant que prestataires de services conformément aux lois applicables, ces fournisseurs peuvent avoir accès à vos données à caractère personnel afin de fournir les services et/ou de se conformer aux obligations découlant des relations juridiques qui existent entre les tiers susmentionnés et nous. Dans tous les cas, nous avons signé les accords de confidentialité et de protection des données correspondants avec ces prestataires de services, en totale conformité avec la législation actuelle sur la protection des données.  
\- **Partenaires de paiement**. Nos partenaires de paiement collectent et traitent des données liées aux paiements et achats à des fins de traitement des paiements et de lutte contre la fraude.  
\- **Partenaires Publicitaires**. Nous pouvons partager votre information afin de vous fournir des publicités plus adaptées et aider à mesurer l'efficacité de celles-ci.  
\- **Partenaires Marketing**. Nous pouvons partager votre information afin de vous permettre de participer à nos promotions, promouvoir nos Services dans d'autres plateformes, et mesurer l'efficacité de nos activités Marketing.  
\- **Nos Sociétés Affiliées**. Nous pouvons partager votre information personnelle avec nos filiales pour des buts décrits dans cette Politique de Confidentialité.  
\- **Autres parties en cas d’exigence légale ou de nécessité pour la protection de nos Services**. Dans certains cas, nous pouvons divulguer vos données à d’autres parties :  
\- pour nous conformer aux lois ou à une procédure judiciaire obligatoire (par exemple mandat de perquisition ou autre injonction judiciaire) ;  
\- pour vérifier ou imposer la conformité aux politiques qui régissent nos Services ; et  
\- pour protéger nos droits, nos biens ou notre sécurité ou, conformément aux lois sur la protection des données, l’une de nos filiales respectives, partenaires commerciaux ou clients.  
\- **Autres parties en lien avec des transactions**. Nous pouvons divulguer vos données à un tiers dans le cadre d’une fusion ou d’une cession, d’une acquisition ou d’une vente, ou en cas de faillite.  
\- **Autres parties avec votre consentement ou à votre demande**. En plus des cas de divulgation décrits dans la présente Politique de protection des données, nous pouvons partager des données vous concernant avec des tiers lorsque vous acceptez ou demandez séparément ce partage.  
\- **Liens vers d'autres sites web, appareils, applications et fonctions**. Le Service peut vous donner la possibilité de vous connecter à d'autres sites web, appareils, applications et fonctions, dont le fonctionnement peut nous être indépendant et être soumis à leurs propres déclarations ou politiques de protection des données, que nous vous conseillons vivement de consulter. Dans la mesure où tout autre site web lié, appareil, application ou autre fonction n’est pas notre propriété ou échappe à notre contrôle, nous ne sommes pas responsables de son contenu, de son utilisation ou de ses pratiques en matière de protection des données.

#### 5\. Conservation des données à caractère personnel

Nous prenons des mesures appropriées pour garantir que nous traitons et conservons les données vous concernant selon la logique suivante :  
\- pendant la durée minimale pendant laquelle les données sont utilisées pour vous fournir un service ;  
\- en application des lois, d’un contrat ou en lien avec nos obligations légales (par exemple en matière fiscale) ; ou  
\- uniquement pendant la durée requise pour les finalités pour lesquelles les données ont été collectées, sont traitées, ou plus longtemps en application d’un contrat, de lois applicables, ou sous forme anonymisée, à des fins statistiques, avec les garanties appropriées.  
  
Nous ne conservons donc vos données à caractère personnel qu’aussi longtemps que nous en avons besoin pour les finalités pour lesquelles nous les collectons et pour nous conformer à des exigences juridiques, financières, commerciales ou de déclaratives. Lorsque nous n’avons plus besoin des données à caractère personnel, nous les supprimons ou détruisons de manière sécurisée. Une fois ces finalités réalisées, vos données à caractère personnel seront supprimées ou détruites de manière sécurisée.  
  
Nous continuons néanmoins à stocker les données collectées après cette date jusqu’à l’expiration de toute obligation juridique en découlant.

#### 6\. Vos droits

Vos données à caractère personnel vous appartiennent. En fonction du territoire dans lequel vous résidez, vous pouvez nous demander des données détaillées sur les données que nous avons collectées et nous demander de rectifier toute inexactitude. Plus précisément, vos droits sont les suivants :

**Votre droit d'accès** : vous avez le droit de nous demander si nous utilisons ou stockons vos données à caractère personnel. Vous pouvez aussi nous demander des copies de vos données à caractère personnel.  
**Votre droit de rectification** : vous avez le droit de nous demander de rectifier toute information que vous jugez inexacte. Vous avez aussi le droit de compléter les données que vous pensez être incomplètes.  
**Votre droit de suppression** : vous avez le droit de nous demander de supprimer vos données à caractère personnel dans les circonstances suivantes : (i) nous n’avons plus besoin de vos données à caractère personnel, (ii) vous avez initialement consenti à l’utilisation de vos données à caractère personnel, mais vous avez ensuite retiré votre consentement, (iii) vous vous êtes opposé à l’utilisation de vos données à caractère personnel et vos intérêts prévalent sur ceux de notre société, (iv) nous avons collecté ou utilisé vos données à caractère personnel de manière illicite, et/ou (v) nous avons l’obligation légale de supprimer vos données à caractère personnel.  
**Votre droit de limiter le traitement** : vous avez le droit de nous demander de limiter le traitement de vos données à caractère personnel dans les circonstances suivantes : (i) vous avez contesté l’exactitude de vos données à caractère personnel, (ii) vous vous êtes opposé à l’utilisation de vos données à caractère personnel, (iii) nous avons traité vos données à caractère personnel de manière illicite sans que vous souhaitiez les supprimer, et/ou (iv) nous n’avons plus besoin de vos données à caractère personnel mais vous souhaitez que nous les conservions afin de défendre ou d’exercer des droits en justice.  
**Votre droit de vous opposer au traitement** : vous avez le droit de vous opposer au traitement de vos données à caractère personnel si nous utilisons vos données à caractère personnel pour (i) une tâche réalisée dans l’intérêt public, (ii) nos intérêts légitimes, (iii) des fins de recherche scientifique ou historique ou des fins statistiques, ou (iv) du marketing direct.  
**Votre droit à la portabilité des données** : ce droit s’applique aux données à caractère personnel que vous nous avez fournies, dans le cas où le traitement est automatisé, basé sur votre consentement ou effectué dans le cadre d’un contrat. Vous avez le droit de nous demander, si cela est possible techniquement, de transférer vos données à caractère personnel à une autre organisation ou de vous les communiquer directement sous un format accessible et lisible par machine.  
**Vous avez aussi le droit de retirer votre consentement** : à tout moment si le traitement est basé sur votre consentement, sans affecter la légalité du traitement basé sur votre consentement avant ce retrait.  
**Vous avez le droit d’introduire une réclamation auprès d’une autorité de contrôle** : vous pouvez introduire une réclamation auprès de l’autorité de contrôle compétente si vous considérez que notre traitement de vos données à caractère personnel enfreint les lois applicables.

#### 7\. Exercer vos droits et possibilités de choix

Si vous souhaitez exercer les droits susmentionnés ou introduire une demande, veuillez nous contacter comme indiqué à la section [Nous contacter](#pp_10_fr) (section 10 de la présente Politique de protection des données). Toutefois, si la loi l’autorise, nous pouvons vous facturer un certain montant pour mettre cette possibilité à votre disposition. Dans le respect des lois applicables, nous pouvons refuser de traiter des requêtes dont le caractère répété est déraisonnable, qui requièrent des efforts techniques disproportionnés, mettent en danger la vie privée d'autrui ou dont l’accès n’est pas requis par les lois locales.

Vous pouvez accéder à vos données à caractère personnel stockées par nos soins ou les corriger à tout moment via la page « Compte » ou « Profil de créateur ».

Vous pouvez nous demander de supprimer vos données à caractère personnel en supprimant votre compte à tout moment. Si vous avez des séries publiées sur CANVAS, vous devez d’abord les supprimer avant de supprimer votre compte. Après la suppression de votre compte, votre profil de compte et votre historique d'abonnement seront définitivement supprimés et ne pourront plus être récupérés. Toute information de nature fiscale que vous nous avez envoyée sera conservée pendant une certaine période, conformément aux lois et réglementations fiscales.

Si vous souhaitez modifier vos préférences en matière de communication (notamment les communications marketing), vous pouvez procéder à ces modifications depuis la page « Compte » ou « Paramètres ». Vous pouvez aussi vous désabonner de nos communications et démarchages commerciaux par email à tout moment en cliquant sur le bouton « Se désabonner » en bas de l’email.

Vous pouvez gérer l’utilisation des cookies optionnels en cliquant sur la solution « Paramètres de cookies » qui s’affiche lorsque vous ouvrez l’application/visitez le site web et à tout moment via les Paramètres de cookies. Pour en savoir plus sur la manière dont nous utilisons les cookies que nous collectons, veuillez consulter notre [Politique de Cookies](https://www.webtoons.com/fr/terms/cookiePolicy). Vous pouvez également limiter ou désactiver certains types de cookies en vous rendant sur les sites [https://www.allaboutcookies.org/](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/) ou [https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1).

#### 8\. Comment nous protégeons vos données à caractère personnel

Nous prenons au sérieux la protection de vos données et mettons en œuvre des mesures de sécurité pour protéger les données que nous collectons en lien avec les Services. La transmission de données par Internet n’est pas totalement sécurisée. Bien que nous fassions tout notre possible pour protéger vos données à caractère personnel, nous ne pouvons pas garantir la sécurité des données que vous nous transmettez. Dans les limites autorisées par les lois applicables, nous rejetons toute forme de responsabilité en cas de divulgation de vos données occasionnées par des erreurs de transmission, à un accès non autorisé par des tiers ou à d’autres causes échappant à notre contrôle.

Vous jouez un rôle important dans le maintien de la sécurité de vos données. Vous ne devez pas partager votre nom d’utilisateur ou le mot de passe de votre compte avec d’autres personnes. Si vous avez des raisons de croire que votre compte n’est plus sécurisé, veuillez nous contacter immédiatement.

#### 9\. Données à caractère personnel des mineurs

Les Services sont conçus pour un public général. Si le consentement d’un parent (ou représentant légal) est requis pour traiter les données à caractère personnel d’un mineur conformément aux lois applicables, nous traitons ces données après l’obtention du consentement du parent (ou représentant légal), dans le respect de la procédure juridique requise.

#### 10\. Nous contacter

\- Vous pouvez envoyer toute question, préoccupation ou demande concernant les Politiques de traitement de vos données à caractère personnel à notre service de gestion des données à caractère personnel à l’adresse suivante : [Customer Care](https://contact-cc.line.me/serviceId/12379/fr/?continue_without_login=true).  
\- Vous pouvez nous contacter en envoyant un email à notre Délégué à la Protection des Données (DPD) à l’adresse suivante : [dpo@webtoonscorp.com](mailto:dpo@webtoonscorp.com)  
\- Dans tous les cas, vous pouvez nous contacter par écrit aux coordonnées suivantes.  
  
NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.  
TechONE Tower1 11-12F,  
131, Bundangnaegok-ro, Bundang-gu,  
Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do,  
République de Corée  
  
NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. et WEBTOON Entertainment Inc. menant des actions conjointes lorsque nécessaire pour se conformer à vos droits, demandes ou réclamations, vous pouvez nous contacter auprès de WEBTOON Entertainment Inc. :  
  
WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.  
5700 Wilshire Blvd Suite 220,  
Los Angeles, CA 90036  
USA

#### 11\. Liens vers d’autres sites web

Vous trouverez sur nos sites web ou dans le contenu que nous vous fournissons (par emails promotionnels ou lors d’événements) des hyperliens pour accéder aux sites web d’autres organisations. Notez bien que la présente Politique de protection des données ne régit pas la manière dont d’autres sociétés traitent vos données à caractère personnel. Nous vous recommandons de lire les politiques de protection des données qui s’appliquent aux autres sites web.

#### 12\. Mises à jour de notre Politique de protection des données

La présente Politique de protection des données peut être mise à jour pour refléter les modifications de nos pratiques de gestion des données à caractère personnel en lien avec le Service, ou toute évolution des lois applicables. Nous publierons un avis sur notre Service pour vous avertir au préalable des changements importants apportés à notre Politique de protection des données et indiquerons dans l’en-tête de l’avis la date de la dernière mise à jour.

#### 13\. Divulgation de données au niveau régional

##### 13.1. Pour les résidents de l’Espace Économique Européen (EEE)

Cette section complète la Politique de protection des données de WEBTOON et s’applique uniquement aux résidents de l’Espace Économique Européen (EEE).  
  
**Comment nous utilisons les données que nous collectons**  
Le tableau ci-dessous communique des données sur les finalités pour lesquelles nous traitons vos données à caractère personnel, les catégories de données à caractère personnel que nous traitons ainsi que le fondement juridique des activités de traitement que nous effectuons.

| Finalité | Catégories de données à caractère personnel | Fondement juridique |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \- Vous identifier, vous authentifier et gérer votre compte ;  <br>\- Fournir un Service ou une fonction que vous avez demandés, par exemple répondre aux demandes, questions et instructions introduites via les Services ;  <br>\- Vous envoyer des données et récompenses pour les campagnes et événements ;  <br>\- Traiter le paiement et la facturation lorsqu’un utilisateur achète un produit ou utilise un Service qui n’est pas gratuit ;  <br>\- Vous envoyer des communications par email ou des notifications au sein d’un produit (par exemple notification pop-up, notification push) en lien avec nos Services, conformément aux préférences de communication que vous définissez ;  <br>\- Répondre à vos demandes d’information et envoyer aux utilisateurs des notifications importantes lorsque nécessaire ;  <br>\- Fournir des récompenses ou primes ou remettre des prix aux participants à une enquête ou aux participants ou vainqueurs d’un concours ;  <br>\- Mettre le PROGRAMME DE PARTAGE DES REVENUS PUBLICITAIRES à disposition des utilisateurs ;  <br>\- Envoyer des emails portant sur votre travail ou votre utilisation, conformément aux préférences d’email que vous avez définies ;  <br>\- Répondre à vos questions. | • Données de contact  <br>• Données de compte  <br>• Données liées au Service Client  <br>• Information de l’image  <br>• Identifiants  <br>• Données de profil des Créateurs  <br>• Identifiant PayPal  <br>• Identifiant Patreon  <br>• Identifiant uTip  <br>• Données sur le paiement des revenus publicitaires :  <br>• Données de profil WEBTOON TRANSLATE :  <br>• Données liées à une candidature comme chef d'équipe WEBTOON TRANSLATE  <br>• Cookies  <br>• Données sur l’utilisation des Services  <br>• Données portant sur l’organisation de concours et/ou opérations promotionnelles :  <br>• Données sur les appareils et données de connexion  <br>• Détails des transactions et achats | Pour mettre nos services à votre disposition, exécuter un contrat ou prendre des mesures liées à un contrat (Art. 6(1)(b)) |
| \- Réaliser les enquêtes et analyses requises pour l’amélioration du Service ;  <br>\- Vous fournir des fonctions adaptées, telle que la recommandation basée sur votre âge et/ou sur les informations de votre utilisation telles que les pages web les plus visitées, et des contenus supplémentaires adaptés à vos intérêts reconnus par le tab Intérêt.  <br>\- Vous envoyer des communications par email ou des notifications au sein d’un produit (par exemple notification pop-up, notification push) en lien avec nos Services, conformément aux préférences de communication que vous définissez ;  <br>\- Identifier, prévenir et protéger contre la fraude et les autres activités criminelles, les demandes de réparation et les autres obligations ;  <br>\- Assurer et surveiller l’efficacité et la disponibilité des services afin d’améliorer les performances du site web et de l’application ;  <br>\- Générer des données statistiques portant sur l’utilisation des services, et  <br>\- Respecter et faire appliquer les normes applicables du secteur ainsi que nos politiques, y compris la présente Politique de protection des données ; | • Données de contact  <br>• Données de compte  <br>• Données liées à des enquêtes  <br>• Information de l’image  <br>• Données de profil des Créateurs  <br>• Données de profil WEBTOON TRANSLATE  <br>• Cookies  <br>• Données sur l’utilisation des Services  <br>• Données portant sur l’organisation de concours et/ou opérations promotionnelles :  <br>• Données sur les appareils et données de connexion  <br>• Détails des transactions et achats  <br>• Données de services d'analyse tiers | Lorsque cela est nécessaire pour protéger nos intérêts légitimes à exercer nos activités et à améliorer nos Services (Art. 6(1)(f)) |
| \- Déposer des cookies et utiliser des technologies similaires conformément à notre Politique de Cookies et aux données qui vous sont communiquées lorsque ces technologies sont utilisées ;  <br>\- Vous envoyer des communications par email portant sur les mises à jour des services, les actualités et les événements ;  <br>\- Vous fournir les publicités qui incluent les publicités ciblées (ou basées sur vos intérêts) ;  <br>\- À d'autres occasions, lorsque nous demandons votre consentement, nous utilisons les données pour la finalité expliquée à ce moment. | • Données de compte  <br>• Cookies  <br>• Données sur l’utilisation des Services | Si vous avez donné votre consentement (Art. 6(1)(a)) |
| \- Respecter et faire appliquer les exigences légales applicables ; et  <br>\- Répondre aux demandes de l’administration ou des autorités chargées du maintien de l’ordre. | • Date de naissance  <br>• Données sur le paiement des revenus publicitaires  <br>• Toutes les catégories données à caractère personnel requises par les lois. | Lorsque les lois l’exigent (Art. 6(1)(c)) |

**Transfert international de données**  
En outre, votre utilisation des Services peut impliquer le transfert, le stockage et le traitement de vos données à caractère personnel dans d'autres pays. L’on retrouve notamment parmi ces pays, et de manière non exhaustive, les pays de l’Espace Économique Européen, les États-Unis, le Japon, la Thaïlande, l’Indonésie, Taïwan, les Philippines et la République de Corée. Nous prendrons toutes les mesures appropriées, conformément aux lois applicables, pour assurer la protection de vos données à caractère personnel. Ces mesures comprennent par exemple l’utilisation des Clauses contractuelles types de la Commission européenne, lorsque celles-ci sont applicables, afin de sécuriser le transfert de données hors de l’EEE et la demande de votre consentement explicite. Par ailleurs, la Commission européenne reconnaît que certains pays et territoires situés hors de l’EEE assurent un niveau de protection adéquat des données à caractère personnel – par le biais de décisions auxquelles il est fait référence par l’expression « décisions d'adéquation ». Lorsque nous transférons des données à caractère personnel depuis l’EEE vers des pays tiers qui ont obtenu ces décisions d'adéquation, nous ne sommes pas obligés de mettre en place des mécanismes alternatifs pour légitimer le transfert (tels que des clauses contractuelles types). Pour demander des données supplémentaires ou obtenir une copie des accords contractuels ou autres mesures de protection mises en place, veuillez nous contacter. Voir la section [Nous contacter](#pp_10_fr) ci-dessus.  
  
**Prise de décision automatisée**  
Nous ne prenons pas de décision pouvant vous affecter sur la seule base du traitement automatisé de vos données à caractère personnel. Toutes les procédures de prise de décision liées aux finalités de traitement susmentionnées sont effectuées avec une intervention humaine.  
  
**Données à caractère personnel des mineurs**  
Avant que vous puissiez utiliser nos services, nous vous demandons de nous communiquer des données sur votre âge pour nous aider à respecter les lois sur la protection des données. Plus spécifiquement, nous vous demandons votre date de naissance afin de déterminer si vous êtes ou non autorisé à utiliser les services, ou si nous devons obtenir le consentement parental vérifiable d’un de vos parents, ou de la personne détentrice de l’autorité légale, avant de vous autoriser à accéder aux services ou à les utiliser. Si le consentement parental des parents ou responsables légaux de l’utilisateur est requis, nous obtenons ce consentement avant de traiter les données à caractère personnel de mineurs.  
  
**Vos droits**  
Vous trouverez les coordonnées de contact de toutes les autorités de contrôle de l’Union Européenne à l’adresse [https://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item\_id=612080](https://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080).  
Lorsque le droit français en matière de protection des données est applicable, vous avez également le droit de définir des directives pour la conservation et la communication de vos données à caractère personnel après votre décès.  
  
Délégué européen à la protection des données  
  
Vous pouvez nous contacter en envoyant un email à notre délégué européen à la protection des données à l’adresse suivante : [eu\_representative@navercorp.com](mailto:eu_representative@navercorp.com)

### POKOK-POKOK KEBIJAKAN PRIVASI WEBTOON™ INDONESIA

Terakhir Diperbarui: 26 Maret 2024.

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. (termasuk afiliasinya, selanjutnya bersama-sama disebut sebagai "**kami**", "**milik kami**", atau "**kita**") menghormati kekhawatiran Anda tentang privasi. Kebijakan Privasi ini berlaku untuk informasi pribadi yang kami kumpulkan melalui aplikasi WEBTOON dan/atau situs web dan KANVAS (secara kolektif disebut "**Layanan**").

#### RINGKASAN KEBIJAKAN PRIVASI

Dalam Kebijakan Privasi ini, kami menjelaskan jenis informasi pribadi yang kami proses melalui Layanan, cara kami menggunakan informasi tersebut, dengan siapa kami dapat membagikannya, dan pilihan yang tersedia bagi Anda terkait penggunaan informasi dan pelaksanaan hak Anda. Kami juga menjelaskan langkah-langkah yang kami ambil untuk mengamankan informasi dan memberi tahu Anda cara menghubungi kami tentang praktik privasi kami. Di bawah ini Anda akan menemukan ringkasan pesan-pesan utama yang terkandung dalam Kebijakan Privasi milik kami. Untuk informasi lebih rinci tentang bagaimana kami memproses informasi Anda, silakan klik judul atau lanjutkan membaca di bawah ini.

### KEBIJAKAN PRIVASI WEBTOON ™ INDONESIA

#### 1\. Pengontrol Data

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. dan WEBTOON Entertainment Inc. berbagi kendali bersama untuk memproses informasi pribadi dan berbagi informasi sebagai pengontrol bersama atas informasi pribadi Anda untuk menyediakan Layanan secara efisien dan sesuai dengan hukum yang berlaku.

Dalam hal apapun, Anda dapat menghubungi kami secara tertulis di alamat berikut:  
  
NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.  
TechONE Tower1 11-12F,  
131, Bundangnaegok-ro, Bundang-gu,  
Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do,  
Republik Korea.  
atau  
  
WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.  
5700 Wilshire Blvd Suite 220,  
Los Angeles, CA 90036  
Amerika Serikat  

#### 2\. Informasi yang Kami Kumpulkan

Informasi pribadi berikut ini dikumpulkan sehubungan dengan Layanan:

##### Informasi yang Anda berikan secara langsung

Saat Anda menggunakan Layanan kami, Anda dapat memberi kami informasi pribadi Anda setelah diberi tahu tentang informasi pribadi pada saat pengumpulan. Misalnya:  
\- Informasi kontak: Ketika pengguna dianggap sebagai anak sesuai dengan hukum yang berlaku di yurisdiksi pengguna, kami dapat memerlukan nama pengguna dan alamat surel wali yang sah untuk mendapatkan persetujuan wali yang sah tergantung pada yurisdiksi Anda. Selain itu, saat Anda berpartisipasi dalam acara atau promosi kami, kami dapat meminta nama, nomor telepon, alamat, alamat surel, dan informasi lain yang diperlukan untuk mengirimkan hadiah dan untuk menanggapi pertanyaan.  
\- Informasi akun: Ketika Anda membuat akun sendiri dan masuk ke akun Anda, kami mungkin memerlukan tanggal lahir, nama panggilan, alamat email, dan kata sandi Anda. Selain itu, saat Anda masuk ke akun pihak ketiga atau ke profil Anda bersama kami, kami mungkin meminta informasi seperti nama panggilan atau foto profil.  
\- Informasi survei: Saat Anda berpartisipasi dalam survei atau jajak pendapat kami, kami dapat meminta nama, nomor telepon, jenis kelamin, dan informasi lain yang dapat diperlukan secara wajar untuk melakukan survei atau pendapat dan memberikan hadiah.  
\- Saat Anda menggunakan TOON FILTER, kami akan mengumpulkan foto dan informasi terkait foto tersebut, termasuk mengidentifikasi objek dan latar belakang yang muncul, serta bentuk dan posisi fitur wajah dan tubuh yang nampak dalam foto. Informasi ini tidak terhubung dengan akun Anda dan hanya digunakan untuk mengaktifkan TOON FILTER serta mendeteksi gambar yang tidak pantas. Mohon diingat bahwa kami tidak menggunakan informasi ini untuk mengidentifikasi individu secara spesifik untuk keperluan peningkatan teknologi kami.  
\- Informasi Layanan Pelanggan: Untuk memberikan tanggapan saat Anda menghubungi Layanan Pelanggan kami, kami dapat mengumpulkan informasi apa pun yang Anda pilih untuk diberikan, seperti permintaan atau pertanyaan Anda. Saat Anda berkomunikasi dengan staf Layanan Pelanggan kami atau orang lain, komunikasi Anda akan dikirimkan melalui sistem kami melalui alamat surel Anda.  
\- Pengidentifikasi seperti pengidentifikasi pribadi unik (seperti (i) pengidentifikasi perangkat (misalnya, cookie, beacon, pixel tag), (ii) pengidentifikasi iklan seluler dan teknologi serupa, (iii) nomor pelanggan, nama samaran unik, atau alias pengguna, (iv) nomor telepon dan bentuk pengenal tetap atau probabilistik lainnya), pengenal online, alamat Protokol Internet, pengidentifikasi serupa lainnya.

\[Untuk Kreator\]

Saat Anda menggunakan [KANVAS](https://www.webtoons.com/id/challenge) dan/atau PROGRAM PEMBAGIAN PENDAPATAN IKLAN, kami dapat perlu mengumpulkan informasi tambahan berikut:  
\- Informasi Profil Kreator: Kami dapat meminta informasi yang telah Anda bagikan secara sukarela kepada publik melalui halaman Profil Kreator Anda, termasuk foto profil, biodata, tautan media sosial, situs web, dan lainnya.  
\- Kami dapat meminta agar ID PayPal atau ID Patreon Anda ditautkan ke Layanan.  
\- Kami dapat meminta ID uTip Anda untuk memberikan hadiah atau bonus.  
\- Informasi Pembagian Pendapatan Iklan: Jika Anda memilih untuk memberikan akun PayPal Anda, kami dapat meminta informasi tambahan seperti Nama Anda (Nama Resmi/Alias Bisnis), Nama Lengkap/Nama Bisnis, Negara, Tempat Tinggal, Alamat, Kode Pos, E- surat, Tanda Tangan dan Identitas Pajak (atau Nomor Jaminan Sosial bila berlaku) untuk tujuan pemrosesan pajak.

\[Untuk Pengguna WEBTOON TRANSLATE\]

Saat Anda menggunakan [WEBTOON TRANSLATE](https://translate.webtoons.com/), kami dapat perlu mengumpulkan informasi tambahan berikut:  
\- Informasi profil: Kami dapat mengumpulkan informasi yang telah Anda bagikan secara sukarela kepada publik melalui halaman profil Anda, termasuk foto profil, nama panggilan, URL situs pengguna, lokasi, dan bahasa pilihan Anda.  
\- Informasi aplikasi manajer tim: Jika Anda melamar sebagai manajer tim, kami dapat meminta URL "Profil Saya" Anda, bahasa pilihan Anda, dan pengalaman penerjemahan lainnya.

##### Informasi dikumpulkan melalui cookie dan teknologi serupa

\- Kami dan pihak ketiga dapat menggunakan cookie, web beacon, pixel, tag, dan teknologi pelacakan lainnya (yang akan kami rujuk secara kolektif sebagai "cookie") untuk membantu kita mengumpulkan informasi statistik guna meningkatkan pengalaman Anda dengan Layanan, menyimpan preferensi, dan untuk memberi Anda penawaran. Cookie ini dapat digunakan untuk melacak Anda di seluruh perangkat dan situs web dari waktu ke waktu. Sebagian besar browser web menerima cookie dan ID sesi secara otomatis, tetapi Anda dapat menonaktifkan cookie dengan membuat pilihan yang sesuai dari opsi browser Anda atau melalui Pengaturan Cookie. Perhatikan bahwa dengan melakukan itu, fungsionalitas Layanan kami dapat terbatas.

Untuk mengetahui lebih lanjut tentang bagaimana kami menggunakan cookie yang dikumpulkan, silakan lihat Kebijakan Cookie kami. Untuk mengetahui lebih lanjut tentang cookie, termasuk cara melihat cookie apa yang telah disetel, kunjungi [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/www.aboutcookies.org) atau [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/www.allaboutcookies.org).

##### Informasi tentang penggunaan layanan Anda

Selain informasi yang Anda berikan, kami akan mengumpulkan informasi tentang penggunaan Layanan kami oleh Anda melalui perangkat lunak di perangkat Anda dan dengan cara lain. Kami akan mengumpulkan:  
\- Informasi penggunaan layanan: interaksi Anda dengan Layanan, tanggal dan waktu penggunaan Layanan dan informasi penggunaan Layanan apa pun seperti membaca preferensi genre, komentar atau suka, saldo Koin dan Pas Gratis, informasi komersial termasuk riwayat pembelian dan transaksi, tampilan terkini , riwayat langganan, riwayat unduhan, dan acara, promosi, dan/atau partisipasi kontes;  
\- Informasi yang berkaitan dengan penyelenggaraan kontes dan/atau operasi promosi apa pun: tanggal partisipasi, tanggapan terhadap kontes, dan sifat hadiah yang ditawarkan;  
\- Informasi Perangkat dan Log: Informasi Perangkat dan Log seperti model perangkat, versi OS, alamat IP, pengaturan perangkat, informasi negara berdasarkan alamat IP, URL, dan jenis jaringan; dan  
\- Perincian Transaksi / Pembelian: kami tidak mengumpulkan atau memproses perincian pembayaran apa pun tentang Anda (misalnya, perincian kartu kredit). Informasi tersebut hanya dikumpulkan dan diproses melalui App Store Apple, Google Play Store, dan PayPal. Satu-satunya informasi yang dapat dibagikan oleh Apple, Google, dan PayPal kepada kami adalah rincian transaksi dan pembelian (mis., nomor transaksi, riwayat pembelian). Informasi tersebut hanya diproses untuk memvalidasi transaksi.  
\- Kesimpulan: Kami dapat menarik kesimpulan tentang minat, preferensi, dan kelompok gender Anda berdasarkan informasi dari interaksi Anda melalui Layanan kami atau mitra pengiklan.

##### Informasi dikumpulkan melalui Analitik Pihak ke-3

\- Melalui Layanan tertentu, kami dapat mengumpulkan informasi pribadi tentang aktivitas online Anda di situs web dan perangkat yang terhubung dari waktu ke waktu dan di seluruh situs web, perangkat, aplikasi, serta fitur dan layanan online pihak ketiga lainnya. Kami dapat menggunakan layanan analitik pihak ketiga di Layanan. Informasi yang kami peroleh dapat diungkapkan atau dikumpulkan secara langsung oleh penyedia ini dan pihak ketiga terkait lainnya yang menggunakan informasi tersebut, misalnya, untuk mengevaluasi penggunaan Layanan atau membantu mengelola Layanan.

#### 3\. Bagaimana Kami Menggunakan Informasi yang Kami Kumpulkan

Kami dapat menggunakan informasi yang dikumpulkan di atas untuk tujuan berikut:

\[Untuk Pengguna dan Kreator\]

\- Mengidentifikasi dan mengautentikasi Anda serta mengelola akun Anda  
\- Menyediakan Layanan atau fitur yang Anda minta, seperti menanggapi permintaan, pertanyaan, dan instruksi Anda yang dibuat melalui Layanan;  
\- Melakukan survei dan analisis yang diperlukan untuk meningkatkan Layanan;  
\- Mengirimkan kepada Anda informasi dan hadiah untuk kampanye dan acara;  
\- Memproses pembayaran dan penagihan saat pengguna membeli produk atau menggunakan Layanan yang tidak gratis;  
\- Memberikan Anda fitur yang disesuaikan seperti rekomendasi berdasarkan usia dan/atau informasi penggunaan layanan seperti halaman web yang paling sering dikunjungi, dan konten tambahan yang disesuaikan dengan minat Anda melalui tab ‘Favorit’;  
\- Memberikan Anda iklan yang mungkin mencakup iklan yang dipersonalisasi atau ditargetkan (atau berdasarkan minat).  
\- Mengirimkan kepada Anda komunikasi melalui surel atau notifikasi dalam produk (misalkan, notifikasi pop-up, notifikasi push) sehubungan dengan Layanan kami sebagaimana dikendalikan oleh preferensi komunikasi Anda;  
\- Memantau dan menganalisis tren, penggunaan, dan aktivitas sehubungan dengan produk dan layanan kami;  
\- Membuat informasi yang tidak teridentifikasi, dianonimkan, atau dikumpulkan;  
\- Memberikan dan melindungi Konten Digital;  
\- Memverifikasi usia dan menyediakan konten dan pengalaman yang sesuai dengan usia.  
\- Memastikan keamanan informasi Layanan kami;  
\- Melindungi, mengidentifikasi, dan mencegah penipuan dan kegiatan kriminal lainnya, klaim, dan kerugian lainnya;  
\- Menghasilkan data statistik yang berkaitan dengan penggunaan Layanan;  
\- Memastikan dan memantau keefektifan dan ketersediaan layanan untuk meningkatkan kinerja situs web dan aplikasi;  
\- Mematuhi dan menegakkan persyaratan hukum yang berlaku, kewajiban hukum kami (misalnya, undang-undang perpajakan), standar industri yang relevan, dan kebijakan kami, termasuk Kebijakan Privasi ini;  
\- Validasi transaksi dan cegah penipuan dan penyalahgunaan;  
\- Menanggapi pertanyaan Anda dan mengirimkan pemberitahuan penting kepada pengguna bila diperlukan; dan  
\- Melaksanakan tujuan lain yang dijelaskan kepada Anda pada saat informasi dikumpulkan.  

\[Untuk Kreator yang menggunakan KANVAS dan/atau PROGRAM PEMBAGIAN PENDAPATAN IKLAN\]

Selain tujuan di atas, kami dapat menggunakan informasi yang dikumpulkan tentang kreator menggunakan [KANVAS](https://www.webtoons.com/id/challenge) dan/atau PROGRAM PEMBAGIAN PENDAPATAN IKLAN untuk tujuan tambahan berikut:  
\- Memberikan hadiah, bonus, atau mengirimkan hadiah kepada peserta survei, peserta kontes, atau pemenang;  
\- Verifikasi identitas Anda untuk mematuhi undang-undang federal yang berlaku;  
\- Menyediakan PROGRAM PEMBAGIAN PENDAPATAN IKLAN kepada pengguna;  
\- Mengirim surel yang relevan dengan pekerjaan atau penggunaan Anda, seperti yang dikontrol oleh preferensi surel Anda;  
\- Membalas pertanyaan Anda;  
\- Memahami cara Anda menggunakan Layanan dan membuat PROGRAM PEMBAGIAN PENDAPATAN IKLAN yang lebih baik;  
\- Menghasilkan data statistik yang berkaitan dengan penggunaan Layanan;  
\- Melakukan penelitian dan pengembangan untuk meningkatkan PROGRAM PEMBAGIAN PENDAPATAN IKLAN dan mengembangkan produk masa depan;  
\- Mematuhi dan menegakkan persyaratan hukum yang berlaku, kewajiban hukum kami (misalnya, undang-undang perpajakan), standar industri yang relevan, dan kebijakan kami, termasuk Kebijakan Privasi ini; dan  
\- Mencegah penipuan dan penyalahgunaan PROGRAM PEMBAGIAN PENDAPATAN IKLAN dan mencegah aktivitas, klaim, dan kewajiban kriminal lainnya.

#### 4\. Berbagi Informasi

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. dan WEBTOON Entertainment Inc. berbagi informasi sebagai pengontrol bersama atas informasi pribadi Anda kapan pun diperlukan untuk menyediakan Layanan secara efisien dan sesuai dengan hukum yang berlaku. Kami mengungkapkan atau membagikan informasi pribadi tentang Anda melalui Layanan sebagaimana dijelaskan berikut ini:  
\- **Informasi yang Tersedia untuk Publik**. Informasi yang Anda daftarkan secara sukarela untuk dibagikan kepada publik dapat dilihat oleh siapa saja, termasuk mereka yang tidak memiliki akun. Ini dapat termasuk nama panggilan Anda, gambar profil, biografi singkat, tautan media sosial, situs web, informasi lain di profil publik Anda, dan informasi atau konten apa pun yang Anda bagikan dengan audiensi publik.  
\- **Penyedia jasa**. Kami dapat mengungkapkan informasi Anda kepada perusahaan yang menyediakan Layanan atas nama kami, seperti perusahaan yang membantu kami mengembangkan dan mengoperasikan sistem untuk Layanan dengan pusat kontak pelanggan, serta aktivitas layanan pelanggan, iklan (termasuk iklan yang disesuaikan di situs web kami, situs web pihak ketiga, atau platform online), melakukan survei kepuasan pelanggan, penagihan atau yang mengirimkan surel atas nama kami. Entitas ini dibatasi oleh ketentuan kontrak dalam kemampuan mereka untuk menggunakan informasi Anda untuk tujuan selain menyediakan Layanan bagi kami.  
Bertindak sebagai penyedia layanan sesuai dengan peraturan hukum, pemasok tersebut dapat memiliki akses ke informasi pribadi Anda untuk menyediakan layanan dan/atau mematuhi kewajiban yang timbul dari hubungan hukum yang terjalin antara pihak ketiga yang disebutkan di atas dan kami. Dalam hal apapun, kami telah menandatangani perjanjian kerahasiaan dan perlindungan data yang sesuai dengan penyedia layanan tersebut, sesuai sepenuhnya dengan ketentuan perundang-undangan saat ini tentang perlindungan data.  
  
\- **Mitra Pembayaran**. Informasi pembayaran dan pembelian dikumpulkan dan diproses oleh mitra pembayaran untuk tujuan pemrosesan pembayaran dan anti-penipuan.  
\- **Mitra Pengiklan**. Kami dapat membagikan informasi Anda untuk menayangkan iklan yang lebih relevan kepada Anda dan membantu mengukur efektivitas iklan.  
\- **Mitra Pemasaran**. Kami dapat membagikan informasi Anda untuk memungkinkan Anda berpartisipasi dalam promosi kami, mempromosikan Layanan kami di platform lain, dan mengukur efektivitas kegiatan Pemasaran kami.  
\- **Perusahaan Afiliasi Kami**. Kami dapat membagikan informasi pribadi Anda dengan anak perusahaan kami untuk tujuan yang telah dijelaskan dalam Kebijakan Privasi ini.  
\- **Pihak Lain Bila Diwajibkan oleh Hukum atau sebagaimana Diperlukan untuk Melindungi Layanan Kami**. Ada kejadian yang dapat terjadi ketika kami mengungkapkan informasi Anda kepada pihak lain:  
\- untuk mematuhi hukum atau menanggapi proses hukum wajib (seperti surat perintah penggeledahan atau perintah pengadilan lainnya);  
\- untuk memverifikasi atau menegakkan kepatuhan terhadap kebijakan yang mengatur Layanan kami; dan  
\- untuk melindungi hak, properti, atau keamanan kami, atau, sesuai dengan undang-undang perlindungan data, afiliasi, mitra bisnis, atau pelanggan kami masing-masing.  
\- **Pihak Lain Sehubungan dengan Transaksi**. Kami dapat mengungkapkan informasi Anda kepada pihak ketiga sebagai bagian dari penggabungan atau pengalihan, akuisisi atau penjualan aktual atau terencana, atau jika terjadi kebangkrutan.  
\- **Pihak Lain dengan Persetujuan Anda atau atas Permintaan Anda**. Selain pengungkapan yang dijelaskan dalam Kebijakan Privasi ini, kami dapat menyampaikan informasi tentang Anda dengan pihak ketiga saat Anda menyetujui atau meminta penyampaian tersebut secara terpisah.  
\- **Tautan ke Situs Web, Perangkat, Aplikasi, dan Fitur Lain**. Layanan dapat menyediakan kemampuan untuk terhubung ke situs web, perangkat, aplikasi, dan fitur lain lainnya, yang dapat beroperasi secara independen dari kami dan dapat memiliki pemberitahuan atau kebijakan privasinya sendiri, yang sangat kami sarankan untuk Anda tinjau. Sejauh situs web, perangkat, aplikasi, atau fitur lain yang ditautkan tidak dimiliki atau dikendalikan oleh kami, kami tidak bertanggung jawab atas konten, penggunaan, atau praktik privasinya.

#### 5\. Penyimpanan Informasi Pribadi

Kami mengambil langkah-langkah yang tepat untuk memastikan bahwa kami memproses dan menyimpan informasi tentang Anda berdasarkan logika berikut:  
\- pada durasi minimum penggunaan informasi untuk menyediakan suatu layanan kepada Anda;  
\- sebagaimana diharuskan oleh undang-undang, kontrak, atau sehubungan dengan kewajiban hukum kami (misalkan, undang-undang perpajakan); atau  
\- hanya selama diperlukan untuk tujuan pengumpulan, pemrosesan, atau lebih lama jika diperlukan berdasarkan kontrak apa pun, oleh undang-undang yang berlaku, atau, dalam bentuk anonim, untuk tujuan statistik, tunduk pada pengamanan yang sesuai.  
  
Oleh karena itu, kami hanya akan menyimpan data pribadi Anda selama kami membutuhkannya untuk tujuan kami mengumpulkannya dan untuk mematuhi persyaratan hukum, keuangan, bisnis, atau pelaporan. Ketika kami tidak lagi membutuhkan informasi pribadi tersebut, kami akan menghapus atau menghancurkannya dengan aman.  
Kami akan menyimpan data yang dikumpulkan bahkan setelahnya, hingga berakhirnya tanggung jawab hukum apa pun yang timbul darinya.

#### 6\. Hak Anda

Informasi pribadi Anda adalah milik Anda. Tergantung pada yurisdiksi tempat Anda tinggal, Anda dapat meminta kami untuk memberikan rincian tentang apa yang telah kami kumpulkan, dan Anda dapat meminta kami untuk memperbaiki ketidakakuratan. Rincian hak Anda adalah sebagai berikut:

**Hak akses Anda**: Anda berhak bertanya kepada kami apakah kami menggunakan atau menyimpan informasi pribadi Anda atau tidak. Anda juga dapat meminta salinan informasi pribadi Anda kepada kami.  
**Hak Anda atas perbaikan**: Anda berhak meminta kami untuk memperbaiki informasi yang menurut Anda tidak akurat. Anda juga berhak untuk melengkapi informasi yang Anda anggap tidak lengkap.  
**Hak Anda untuk menghapus**: Anda memiliki hak untuk meminta kami menghapus informasi pribadi Anda dalam keadaan berikut: (i) kami tidak lagi memerlukan informasi pribadi Anda, (ii) Anda awalnya menyetujui penggunaan informasi pribadi Anda, tetapi sekarang telah menarik persetujuan Anda, (iii) Anda keberatan dengan penggunaan informasi pribadi Anda dan kepentingan Anda melebihi kepentingan perusahaan kami, (iv) kami telah mengumpulkan atau menggunakan informasi pribadi Anda secara tidak sah, dan/atau (v) kami memiliki kewajiban hukum untuk menghapus informasi pribadi Anda.  
**Hak Anda untuk membatasi pemrosesan**: Anda berhak meminta kami untuk membatasi pemrosesan informasi pribadi Anda dalam keadaan berikut: (i) Anda mempertanyakan keakuratan informasi pribadi Anda, (ii) Anda keberatan dengan penggunaan informasi pribadi, (iii) kami memproses informasi pribadi Anda secara tidak sah tanpa Anda ingin menghapusnya, dan/atau (iv) kami tidak lagi memerlukan informasi pribadi Anda tetapi Anda ingin kami menyimpannya untuk membela atau melakukan tuntutan hukum.  
**Hak Anda untuk menolak pemrosesan**: Anda memiliki hak untuk menolak pemrosesan informasi pribadi Anda jika kami menggunakan informasi pribadi Anda untuk (i) tugas yang dilakukan demi kepentingan publik, (ii) kepentingan sah kami, (iii) penelitian ilmiah atau sejarah atau tujuan statistik, atau (iv) pemasaran langsung.  
**Hak Anda atas portabilitas data**: hak ini berlaku untuk informasi pribadi yang Anda berikan kepada kami dan di mana pemrosesan dilakukan secara otomatis, berdasarkan persetujuan Anda atau dibuat berdasarkan kontrak. Anda berhak meminta kami, jika memungkinkan secara teknis, untuk mentransfer informasi pribadi Anda ke organisasi lain atau secara langsung memberikannya kepada Anda dengan cara yang dapat diakses dan dapat dibaca oleh mesin.  
**Anda juga memiliki hak untuk menarik persetujuan**: setiap saat pemrosesan didasarkan pada persetujuan Anda, tanpa mempengaruhi keabsahan pemrosesan berdasarkan persetujuan sebelum penarikan tersebut.  
**Anda memiliki hak untuk mengajukan keluhan kepada otoritas pengawas**: Anda dapat mengajukan keluhan kepada otoritas pengawas terkait jika Anda menganggap bahwa pemrosesan informasi pribadi Anda oleh kami melanggar hukum yang berlaku.

#### 7\. Menjalankan Hak dan Pilihan Anda

Jika Anda ingin menggunakan hak di atas atau jika Anda ingin mengirimkan permintaan Anda, silakan hubungi kami seperti yang ditentukan di bagian [Hubungi Kami](#pp_10_id) (bagian 10 dari Kebijakan Privasi ini). Namun, jika diizinkan oleh undang-undang, kami dapat membebankan biaya kecil kepada Anda untuk menyediakan kemampuan ini kepada Anda. Tunduk pada hukum yang berlaku, kami dapat menolak untuk memproses permintaan yang diulang-ulang secara tidak wajar, memerlukan upaya teknis yang tidak proporsional, membahayakan privasi orang lain, atau yang aksesnya tidak diwajibkan oleh hukum setempat.

Anda dapat mengakses atau mengoreksi informasi pribadi Anda yang terdaftar dengan kita kapan saja melalui halaman "Akun" atau "Profil Kreator".

Anda dapat meminta kami untuk menghapus informasi pribadi Anda dengan menghapus akun Anda kapan saja. Jika Anda memiliki seri yang dipublikasikan di KANVAS, Anda harus menghapusnya terlebih dahulu untuk menghapus akun Anda. Setelah Anda menghapus akun, profil akun dan riwayat langganan Anda akan dihapus secara permanen dan tidak dapat dipulihkan. Setiap informasi pajak yang diserahkan kepada kami akan dipertahankan untuk jangka waktu tertentu, sebagaimana disyaratkan oleh undang-undang dan peraturan keuangan.

Jika Anda ingin mengubah preferensi Anda mengenai komunikasi kami (termasuk komunikasi pemasaran), Anda dapat mengubah preferensi komunikasi Anda dari halaman "Akun" atau halaman "Pengaturan". Anda juga dapat berhenti berlangganan komunikasi pemasaran surel kami kapan saja dengan mengeklik tautan "berhenti berlangganan" di bagian bawah surel.

Anda dapat mengelola penggunaan cookie opsional dengan mengeklik solusi "Pengaturan Cookie" yang ditampilkan saat Anda membuka aplikasi/mengunjungi situs web dan kapan saja melalui Pengaturan Cookie. Untuk mengetahui lebih lanjut tentang bagaimana kami menggunakan cookie yang dikumpulkan, silakan lihat Kebijakan Cookie kami. Anda juga dapat membatasi atau menonaktifkan jenis cookie tertentu dengan mengunjungi [https://www.allaboutcookies.org/](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/) atau [https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1).

#### 8\. Bagaimana Kami Melindungi Informasi Pribadi

Kami melindungi informasi Anda dengan serius dan mempertahankan perlindungan yang dirancang untuk melindungi informasi yang kami kumpulkan sehubungan dengan Layanan. Transmisi informasi melalui internet tidak sepenuhnya aman. Meskipun kami akan melakukan yang terbaik untuk melindungi informasi pribadi Anda, kami tidak dapat menjamin keamanan informasi Anda saat dikirimkan kepada kami. Sejauh diizinkan oleh undang-undang yang berlaku, kami tidak berkewajiban atau bertanggung jawab atas pengungkapan informasi Anda karena kesalahan transmisi, akses tidak sah oleh pihak ketiga atau penyebab lain di luar kendali kami.

Anda memainkan peran penting dalam menjaga keamanan informasi Anda. Anda tidak boleh membagikan nama pengguna atau kata sandi untuk akun Anda dengan siapa pun. Jika Anda memiliki alasan untuk meyakini bahwa akun Anda tidak lagi aman, harap segera hubungi kami.

#### 9\. Informasi Pribadi Anak

Layanan dirancang untuk masyarakat umum. Jika persetujuan orang tua (atau wali yang sah) diperlukan untuk memproses informasi pribadi anak sesuai dengan hukum yang berlaku, kami akan memproses informasi tersebut setelah mendapatkan persetujuan dari orang tua (atau wali yang sah) sesuai dengan proses yang diwajibkan secara hukum.

#### 10\. Hubungi Kami

\- Jika Anda memiliki pertanyaan, kekhawatiran, atau pertanyaan tentang Kebijakan untuk menangani informasi pribadi, Anda dapat mengirimkannya ke departemen manajemen informasi pribadi kami di: [Layanan Pelanggan](https://contact-cc.line.me/webtoon/id/).  
\- Anda dapat menghubungi kami dengan mengirimkan surel ke Data Protection Officer (DPO) kami di alamat berikut: [dpo@webtoonscorp.com](mailto:dpo@webtoonscorp.com)  
\- Dalam hal apapun, Anda dapat menghubungi kami secara tertulis di alamat berikut.  
  
NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.  
TechONE Tower1 11-12F,  
131, Bundangnaegok-ro, Bundang-gu,  
Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do,  
Republik Korea.  
  
Karena NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. dan WEBTOON Entertainment Inc. akan mengambil tindakan bersama kapan pun diperlukan untuk mematuhi hak, permintaan, atau keluhan Anda, Anda juga dapat menghubungi kami di WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.:  
  
WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.  
5700 Wilshire Blvd Suite 220,  
Los Angeles, CA 90036  
Amerika Serikat

#### 11\. Tautan ke Situs Web Lain

Anda dapat mengidentifikasi hyperlink untuk mengakses situs web organisasi lain di situs web kami atau di konten yang kami sediakan untuk Anda (misalkan, surel promosi atau acara). Harap diperhatikan bahwa kebijakan privasi ini tidak mencakup bagaimana perusahaan lain akan memproses informasi pribadi Anda. Kami menyarankan Anda untuk membaca kebijakan privasi yang berlaku untuk situs web lain tersebut.

#### 12\. Pembaruan Kebijakan Privasi Kami

Kebijakan Privasi ini dapat diperbarui untuk mencerminkan perubahan dalam praktik informasi pribadi kami sehubungan dengan Layanan, atau perubahan dalam undang-undang yang berlaku. Kami akan memposting pemberitahuan di Layanan kami untuk memberi tahu Anda sebelumnya tentang perubahan materi pada Kebijakan Privasi milik kami dan menunjukkan di bagian atas pemberitahuan kapan pembaruan terakhir dilakukan.

### นโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวของ WEBTOON สำหรับประเทศไทย

อัปเดตล่าสุด: 26 มีนาคม 2024

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. (รวมถึงบริษัทในเครือของบริษัทดังกล่าว ซึ่งต่อไปในข้อกำหนดการใช้งานฉบับนี้จะเรียกรวมกันว่า "เรา" หรือ "ของเรา") เคารพความเป็นส่วนตัวของท่าน นโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวนี้ใช้บังคับกับข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลที่เราเก็บรวบรวมผ่านทางแอปพลิเคชันและ/หรือเว็บไซต์ของ WEBTOON WEBTOON TRANSLATE และ แคนวาส (CANVAS) (ต่อไปนี้จะเรียกรวมกันว่า "**บริการ**")

#### ภาพรวมของนโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัว

ในนโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวนี้ เราอธิบายถึงประเภทของข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลที่เราประมวลผลผ่านบริการ เราอาจใช้ข้อมูลดังกล่าวอย่างไร บุคคลที่เราอาจเปิดเผยข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลดังกล่าวไปให้ และทางเลือกต่าง ๆ ของท่านเกี่ยวกับการใช้ข้อมูลและการใช้สิทธิของท่าน เรายังอธิบายมาตรการที่เราใช้ในการคุ้มครองข้อมูล และแจ้งวิธีการติดต่อเราเกี่ยวกับแนวทางปฏิบัติด้านความเป็นส่วนตัวของเรา ท่านสามารถอ่านสรุปเนื้อหาสำคัญของนโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวของเราได้ด้านล่างนี้ สำหรับรายละเอียดเพิ่มเติมเกี่ยวกับแนวทางการประมวลผลข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่าน โปรดคลิกที่หัวข้อหรืออ่านรายละเอียดด้านล่างนี้

### นโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวของ WEBTOON™ สำหรับประเทศไทย

#### 1\. ผู้ควบคุมข้อมูลส่วนบุคคล

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. และWEBTOON Entertainment Inc. มีอำนาจควบคุมการประมวลผลข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลและแบ่งปันข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลร่วมกัน ในฐานะผู้ควบคุมข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลร่วม เพื่อให้บริการได้อย่างมีประสิทธิภาพและเป็นไปตามกฎหมายที่ใช้บังคับ

ในกรณีใด ๆ ก็ตาม ท่านสามารถติดต่อเราเป็นลายลักษณ์อักษรได้ตามที่อยู่ด้านล่างนี้  
  
NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.  
TechONE Tower1 11-12F,  
131, Bundangnaegok-ro, Bundang-gu,  
Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do,  
Republic of Korea  
หรือ  
  
WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.  
5700 Wilshire Blvd Suite 220,  
Los Angeles, CA 90036  
United States

#### 2\. ข้อมูลที่เราเก็บรวบรวม

เราเก็บรวบรวมข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลที่เกี่ยวกับบริการดังต่อไปนี้

##### ข้อมูลที่ท่านให้โดยตรง

เมื่อท่านเข้าใช้บริการของเรา ท่านอาจให้ข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านกับเราหลังจากที่ท่านได้รับแจ้งข้อมูลความเป็นส่วนตัวในขณะที่เก็บรวบรวมข้อมูลส่วนบุคคล ตัวอย่างเช่น  
\- ข้อมูลติดต่อ: หากผู้ใช้งานเป็นผู้เยาว์ตามกฎหมายที่ใช้บังคับในประเทศของผู้ใช้งาน เราอาจจำเป็นต้องทราบชื่อของผู้ใช้งานและที่อยู่อีเมลของผู้ใช้อำนาจปกครองที่มีอำนาจกระทำการแทนผู้เยาว์เพื่อขอความยินยอมจากผู้ใช้อำนาจปกครองที่มีอำนาจกระทำการแทนผู้เยาว์ ทั้งนี้ ขึ้นอยู่กับประเทศของท่าน นอกจากนี้ เมื่อท่านเข้าร่วมกิจกรรมหรือโปรโมชั่นของเรา เราอาจขอทราบชื่อ หมายเลขโทรศัพท์ ที่อยู่ ที่อยู่อีเมล และข้อมูลอื่น ๆ ที่จำเป็นสำหรับการจัดส่งรางวัลและการตอบคำถาม  
\- ข้อมูลบัญชี: เมื่อคุณสร้างบัญชีของคุณเองและเข้าสู่ระบบบัญชีของคุณเราอาจต้องการวันเกิด ชื่อเล่น ที่อยู่อีเมล และรหัสผ่านของคุณ นอกจากนี้เมื่อคุณเข้าสู่ระบบบัญชีของบุคคลที่สามหรือโปรไฟล์ของคุณกับเรา เราอาจขอข้อมูลเช่นชื่อเล่นหรือรูปโปรไฟล์  
\- ข้อมูลการสำรวจ: เมื่อท่านร่วมทำแบบสำรวจหรือโพลสำรวจความคิดเห็นของเรา เราอาจขอทราบชื่อ หมายเลขโทรศัพท์ เพศ และข้อมูลอื่นใดที่จำเป็นตามสมควรสำหรับการจัดทำแบบสำรวจหรือโพลสำรวจความคิดเห็น และการจัดส่งรางวัล  
\- ข้อมูลรายละเอียดของภาพ: เมื่อคุณเลือกใช้ตูนฟิลเตอร์ เราอาจรวบรวมภาพถ่ายและรวบรวมข้อมูลเกี่ยวกับภาพต่างๆ รวมถึงการระบุวัตถุและทัศนียภาพต่างๆ ที่ปรากฏ รวมทั้งการปรากฏและตำแหน่งของลักษณะใบหน้าและร่างกายและคุณสมบัติต่างๆ ภายในภาพถ่ายของคุณ ข้อมูลนี้ไม่ได้เชื่อมโยงกับบัญชีผู้ใช้ของคุณ และถูกใช้เพื่อเปิดใช้งานลูกเล่นกตูนฟิลเตอร์และตรวจจับภาพที่ไม่เหมาะสม โปรดทราบว่าเราไม่ได้ใช้ข้อมูลนี้ในการระบุบุคคลเฉพาะหรือเพื่อวัตถุประสงค์ของการฝึกอบรมหรือปรับปรุงเทคโนโลยีของเรา  
\- ข้อมูลด้านการดูแลลูกค้า: ในการตอบกลับเมื่อท่านติดต่อ[ฝ่ายดูแลลูกค้า (Customer Care)](https://contact-cc.line.me/serviceId/12379/th/?continue_without_login=true) ของเรา เราอาจเก็บรวบรวมข้อมูลใด ๆ ที่ท่านเลือกที่จะให้ เช่น คำขอหรือข้อซักถามของท่าน เมื่อท่านสื่อสารกับเจ้าหน้าที่ดูแลลูกค้าของเราหรือเจ้าหน้าที่อื่น ๆ ข้อมูลการสื่อสารของท่านจะถูกส่งเข้าระบบของเราผ่านที่อยู่อีเมลของท่าน  
\- ตัวบ่งชี้ (Identifiers) เช่น ตัวบ่งชี้เฉพาะ (Unique Personal Identifier) (เช่น (1) ตัวบ่งชี้อุปกรณ์ (เช่น คุกกี้ บีคอน (Beacons) และพิกเซลแท็ก (Pixel Tags)) (2) ตัวบ่งชี้ในโทรศัพท์เคลื่อนที่ (Mobile Ad Identifiers) และเทคโนโลยีอื่น ๆ ที่คล้ายกัน (3) รหัสลูกค้า นามแฝงเฉพาะ (Unique Pseudonym) หรือนามแฝงของผู้ใช้งาน (User Alias) (4) หมายเลขโทรศัพท์ และตัวบ่งชี้ถาวร (Persistent Identifiers) หรือตัวบ่งชี้ที่น่าจะเป็น (Probabilistic Identifiers) ในรูปแบบอื่น ๆ) ตัวบ่งชี้ออนไลน์ หมายเลขประจำเครื่องคอมพิวเตอร์ (IP Address) และตัวบ่งชี้อื่น ๆ ที่คล้ายกัน

\[สำหรับครีเอเตอร์ (Creators)\]

เมื่อท่านเข้าใช้งาน [แคนวาส (CANVAS)](https://www.webtoons.com/th/challenge) และ/หรือ โปรแกรมแบ่งปันรายได้จากโฆษณา (AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAM) เราอาจจำเป็นต้องเก็บรวบรวมข้อมูลเพิ่มเติมดังต่อไปนี้  
\- ข้อมูลโปรไฟล์ครีเอเตอร์: เราอาจขอข้อมูลที่ท่านเลือกเปิดเผยต่อสาธารณะผ่านทางหน้าโปรไฟล์ครีเอเตอร์ของท่าน เช่น รูปโปรไฟล์ ประวัติส่วนตัว ลิงก์สื่อสังคมออนไลน์ เว็บไซต์ และอื่น ๆ  
\- เราอาจขอให้ท่านเชื่อม PayPal ID และ Patreon ID เข้ากับบริการ  
\- เราอาจขอทราบ uTip ID ของท่านสำหรับการให้รางวัลหรือโบนัส  
\- ข้อมูลการชำระเงิน AD Revenue (AD Revenue Payment Information): หากท่านเลือกที่จะให้ข้อมูลบัญชี PayPal ของท่าน เราอาจขอข้อมูลเพิ่มเติม เช่น ชื่อของท่าน (ชื่อตามกฎหมาย/ชื่อทางธุรกิจ) ชื่อเต็ม/ชื่อธุรกิจ ประเทศ ที่อยู่อาศัย ที่อยู่ รหัสไปรษณีย์ ที่อยู่อีเมล ลายมือชื่อ และหมายเลขประจำตัวผู้เสียภาษี (หรือหมายเลขประกันสังคม (ถ้ามี)) เพื่อวัตถุประสงค์ด้านการดำเนินการทางภาษี

\[สำหรับผู้ใช้งาน WEBTOON TRANSLATE\]

เมื่อท่านใช้งาน [WEBTOON TRANSLATE](https://translate.webtoons.com/) เราอาจจำเป็นต้องเก็บรวบรวมข้อมูลเพิ่มเติมดังต่อไปนี้  
\- ข้อมูลโปรไฟล์: เราอาจเก็บรวบรวมข้อมูลที่ท่านเลือกที่จะเปิดเผยต่อสาธารณะผ่านทางหน้าโปรไฟล์ของท่าน เช่น รูปโปรไฟล์ ชื่อเล่น ที่อยู่ที่ระบุตำแหน่งหน้าเว็บไซต์ (URL) ของหน้าผู้ใช้งาน ตำแหน่งที่ตั้ง และภาษาที่ท่านเลือก  
\- ข้อมูลการสมัครเป็นผู้จัดการทีม: หากท่านสมัครเป็นผู้จัดการทีม เราอาจขอทราบที่อยู่ที่ระบุตำแหน่งหน้าเว็บไซต์ (URL) ของหน้า "โปรไฟล์ของฉัน (My Profile)" ภาษาที่ท่านเลือก และประสบการณ์การแปลอื่น ๆ ของท่าน

##### ข้อมูลที่เก็บรวบรวมผ่านคุกกี้และเทคโนโลยีอื่น ๆ ที่คล้ายกัน

\- เราและบุคคลภายนอกอาจใช้คุกกี้ เว็บบีคอน (Web beacons) พิกเซล (Pixels) แท็ก (Tags) และเทคโนโลยีการติดตามอื่น ๆ (ต่อไปนี้จะเรียกรวมกันว่า "คุกกี้") เพื่อช่วยเราเก็บรวบรวมข้อมูลทางสถิติเพื่อใช้ปรับปรุงประสบการณ์ที่ท่านได้รับจากบริการ บันทึกความชอบ/ความสนใจของท่าน และนำเสนอข้อเสนอต่าง ๆ แก่ท่าน คุกกี้เหล่านี้อาจใช้ในการติดตามการใช้งานอุปกรณ์และเว็บไซต์ต่าง ๆ ของท่านในช่วงเวลาหนึ่ง เว็บเบราว์เซอร์ส่วนใหญ่จะยอมรับคุกกี้และเซสชันไอดี (Session IDs) โดยอัตโนมัติ แต่ท่านอาจสามารถปิดใช้งานคุกกี้ได้โดยกำหนดตัวเลือกที่เหมาะสมในเมนูตั้งค่าเบราว์เซอร์ของท่านหรือผ่าน[การตั้งค่าคุกกี้ (Cookie Settings)](https://www.webtoons.com/th/cookieSetting) ทั้งนี้ โปรดทราบว่าการเปลี่ยนการตั้งค่าดังกล่าวอาจจำกัดฟังก์ชันการทำงานของบริการของเราได้

โปรดอ่าน[นโยบายคุกกี้ (Cookies Policy)](https://www.webtoons.com/th/terms/cookiePolicy) ของเราเพิ่มเติมเกี่ยวกับแนวทางการใช้คุกกี้ที่เก็บรวบรวมไว้ สำหรับข้อมูลเพิ่มเติมเกี่ยวกับคุกกี้ รวมถึงวิธีเข้าดูการตั้งค่าคุกกี้ กรุณาไปที่ [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/www.aboutcookies.org) หรือ [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/www.allaboutcookies.org)

##### ข้อมูลเกี่ยวกับการใช้บริการของท่าน

นอกเหนือจากข้อมูลที่ท่านให้ เราจะเก็บรวบรวมข้อมูลเกี่ยวกับการใช้บริการของท่านผ่านทางซอฟต์แวร์บนอุปกรณ์ของท่าน และด้วยวิธีการอื่น ๆ โดยเราจะเก็บรวบรวมข้อมูลดังต่อไปนี้  
\- ข้อมูลการใช้บริการ: ปฏิสัมพันธ์ของท่านกับบริการ วันที่และเวลาที่ใช้บริการ และข้อมูลการใช้บริการใด ๆ เช่น ประเภทเนื้อหาที่ท่านสนใจอ่าน ความคิดเห็นหรือยอดไลก์ (Likes) ยอดคงเหลือของเหรียญ (Coins) และตั๋วอ่านฟรี (Free Passes) และข้อมูลเชิงพาณิชย์ เช่น ประวัติการซื้อและการทำธุรกรรม การเข้าดูล่าสุด (Recent Views) ประวัติการสมัครสมาชิก (Subscription History) ประวัติการดาวน์โหลด และข้อมูลการเข้าร่วมกิจกรรม โปรโมชั่น และ/หรือการแข่งขัน  
\- ข้อมูลเกี่ยวกับการจัดการแข่งขันและ/หรือการดำเนินการส่งเสริมการขาย: วันที่เข้าร่วม การตอบกลับการแข่งขัน และลักษณะของรางวัลที่ได้รับการเสนอ  
\- ข้อมูลอุปกรณ์และข้อมูลจราจรทางคอมพิวเตอร์ (Log): ข้อมูลอุปกรณ์และข้อมูลจราจรทางคอมพิวเตอร์ (Log) เช่น รุ่นอุปกรณ์ เวอร์ชั่นระบบปฏิบัติการ หมายเลขประจำเครื่องคอมพิวเตอร์ (IP Address) การตั้งค่าอุปกรณ์ ข้อมูลประเทศตามหมายเลขประจำเครื่องคอมพิวเตอร์ (IP Address) ที่อยู่ที่ระบุตำแหน่งหน้าเว็บไซต์ (URL) และประเภทเครือข่าย และ  
\- รายละเอียดการทำธุรกรรม/การซื้อ: เราจะไม่เก็บรวบรวมหรือประมวลผลรายละเอียดการชำระเงินใด ๆ ที่เกี่ยวข้องกับท่าน (เช่น รายละเอียดบัตรเครดิต) ทั้งนี้ ข้อมูลดังกล่าวจะถูกเก็บรวบรวมและประมวลผลผ่านทาง App Store ของ Apple หรือ Google Play Store และ PayPal เท่านั้น ข้อมูลเดียวที่ Apple Google และ PayPal อาจแบ่งปันให้กับเราคือรายละเอียดการทำธุรกรรมและการซื้อ (เช่น หมายเลขธุรกรรม และประวัติการซื้อ) ทั้งนี้ ข้อมูลดังกล่าวจะถูกประมวลผลเพื่อใช้ยืนยันการทำธุรกรรมเท่านั้น  
\- การอนุมาน: เราสามารถเก็บข้อมูลความสนใจ ความชอบ และเพศของคุณ โดยอ้างอิงจากการโต้ตอบของคุณผ่านบริการหรือคู่ค้าโฆษณาของเรา

##### ข้อมูลที่เก็บรวบรวมผ่านการวิเคราะห์ข้อมูลโดยบุคคลภายนอก

\- ในบริการบางอย่าง เราอาจเก็บรวบรวมข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลเกี่ยวกับกิจกรรมออนไลน์ของท่านบนเว็บไซต์และอุปกรณ์ที่ใช้เชื่อมต่อในช่วงเวลาหนึ่ง และบนเว็บไซต์ อุปกรณ์ แอปพลิเคชัน ฟีเจอร์ และบริการออนไลน์อื่น ๆ ของบุคคลภายนอก เราอาจใช้บริการวิเคราะห์ข้อมูลของบุคคลภายนอกในการให้บริการของเรา ข้อมูลที่เราได้รับอาจถูกเปิดเผยไปยังหรือถูกเก็บรวบรวมโดยตรงโดยผู้ให้บริการเหล่านี้ และบุคคลภายนอกอื่น ๆ ที่เกี่ยวข้องที่ใช้ข้อมูลดังกล่าวในการประเมินการใช้บริการหรือช่วยบริหารจัดการบริการ เป็นต้น

#### 3\. เราใช้ข้อมูลที่เก็บรวบรวมอย่างไร

เราอาจใช้ข้อมูลที่เก็บรวบรวมไว้ตามข้างต้นเพื่อวัตถุประสงค์ดังต่อไปนี้

\[สำหรับผู้ใช้งานและครีเอเตอร์\]

\- ระบุและยืนยันตัวตนของท่าน และจัดการบัญชีผู้ใช้ของท่าน  
\- ให้บริการหรือฟีเจอร์ที่ท่านร้องขอ เช่น ตอบกลับคำขอ คำถาม และคำสั่งของท่านที่ทำผ่านบริการ  
\- ดำเนินการสำรวจและวิเคราะห์ที่จำเป็นสำหรับการปรับปรุงบริการ  
\- นำส่งข้อมูลและรางวัลในแคมเปญและกิจกรรมต่าง ๆ ให้กับท่าน  
\- ประมวลผลการชำระเงินและการเรียกเก็บเงินเมื่อผู้ใช้งานซื้อผลิตภัณฑ์หรือใช้บริการที่ต้องชำระเงิน  
\- จัดการฟังก์ชันแนะนำเนื้อหาด้วยตนเองโดยอ้างอิงจากอายุรวมถึงข้อมูลการใช้บริการต่าง ๆ ของผู้ใช้ เช่น เว็บไซต์ที่เข้าชมบ่อยและเนื้อเพิ่มเติมที่ตรงกับความสนใจผ่าน "แท็บความสนใจ(interest tab)"  
\- โฆษณาที่อาจรวมถึงโฆษณาที่ปรับให้เหมาะสมหรือเป้าหมาย (หรือขึ้นอยู่กับความสนใจ)  
\- ส่งข้อความการสื่อสารต่าง ๆ ถึงท่านทางอีเมลหรือการแจ้งเตือนโดยตรงจากผลิตภัณฑ์ (เช่น การแจ้งเตือนที่ขึ้นบนหน้าจอ (Pop-up Notification) และการแจ้งเตือนแบบแสดงในแถบแจ้งเตือน (Push notification)) ที่เกี่ยวกับบริการของเราที่เป็นไปตามการตั้งค่าการสื่อสาร (Communication Preferences) ของท่าน  
\- ติดตามตรวจสอบและวิเคราะห์แนวโน้ม การใช้งาน และกิจกรรมที่เกี่ยวข้องกับผลิตภัณฑ์และบริการของเรา  
\- สร้างข้อมูลที่ไม่ระบุตัวตน ข้อมูลนิรนาม หรือข้อมูลรวม (Aggregated information)  
\- จัดให้มีและคุ้มครองเนื้อหาดิจิทัล (Digital Content)  
\- ตรวจสอบอายุและให้บริการเนื้อหาและประสบการณ์ที่เหมาะสมกับอายุ  
\- รับรองความปลอดภัยของข้อมูลในบริการของเรา  
\- ระงับ ระบุ และป้องกันการฉ้อโกงและอาชญากรรมอื่น ๆ รวมถึงการเรียกร้องและความรับผิดอื่น ๆ  
\- สร้างข้อมูลสถิติเกี่ยวกับการใช้บริการ  
\- รับรองและติดตามตรวจสอบประสิทธิผลและความพร้อมใช้งานของบริการเพื่อปรับปรุงประสิทธิภาพการทำงานของเว็บไซต์และแอปพลิเคชัน  
\- ปฏิบัติตามและบังคับใช้ข้อกำหนดของกฎหมายที่ใช้บังคับ ภาระผูกพันตามกฎหมายของเรา (เช่น กฎหมายภาษีอากร) มาตรฐานอุตสาหกรรมที่เกี่ยวข้อง และนโยบายของเรา รวมถึงนโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวนี้  
\- ยืนยันการทำธุรกรรม และป้องกันการฉ้อโกงและการละเมิด  
\- ตอบกลับคำถามของท่าน และส่งการแจ้งเตือนที่สำคัญให้กับผู้ใช้งานเมื่อจำเป็น และ  
\- ดำเนินการตามวัตถุประสงค์อื่นใดที่ได้แจ้งให้ท่านทราบในขณะที่เก็บรวบรวมข้อมูล

\[สำหรับครีเอเตอร์ที่ใช้งาน แคนวาส (CANVAS) และ/หรือ โปรแกรมแบ่งปันรายได้จากโฆษณา (AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAM)\]

นอกเหนือจากวัตถุประสงค์ข้างต้นแล้ว เราอาจใช้ข้อมูลที่เก็บรวบรวมจากครีเอเตอร์ที่ใช้งาน [แคนวาส (CANVAS)](https://www.webtoons.com/th/challenge) และ/หรือโปรแกรมแบ่งปันรายได้จากโฆษณา (AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAM) เพื่อวัตถุประสงค์เพิ่มเติมดังต่อไปนี้  
\- ให้รางวัลหรือโบนัส หรือนำส่งรางวัลแก่ผู้ร่วมทำแบบสำรวจ ผู้เข้าร่วมแข่งขัน หรือผู้ชนะ  
\- พิสูจน์ยืนยันตัวตนของท่านเพื่อให้เป็นไปตามกฎหมายของรัฐบาลกลางที่ใช้บังคับ  
\- จัดให้มีโปรแกรมแบ่งปันรายได้จากโฆษณา (AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAM) แก่ผู้ใช้งาน  
\- ส่งอีเมลที่เกี่ยวกับผลงานหรือการใช้งานของท่าน ตามการตั้งค่าอีเมลของท่าน  
\- ตอบคำถามของท่าน  
\- ทำความเข้าใจแนวทางการใช้บริการของท่าน และพัฒนาโปรแกรมแบ่งปันรายได้จากโฆษณา (AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAMs) ให้ดียิ่งขึ้น  
\- สร้างข้อมูลสถิติเกี่ยวกับการใช้บริการ  
\- ดำเนินการวิจัยและพัฒนาเพื่อปรับปรุงโปรแกรมแบ่งปันรายได้จากโฆษณา (AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAM) และพัฒนาผลิตภัณฑ์ในอนาคต  
\- ปฏิบัติตามและบังคับใช้ข้อกำหนดของกฎหมายที่ใช้บังคับ ภาระผูกพันตามกฎหมายของเรา (เช่น กฎหมายภาษีอากร) มาตรฐานอุตสาหกรรมที่เกี่ยวข้อง และนโยบายของเรา รวมถึงนโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวนี้  
\- ป้องกันการฉ้อโกงและการใช้โปรแกรมแบ่งปันรายได้จากโฆษณา (AD REVENUE SHARING PROGRAM) ในทางที่ผิด และป้องกันอาชญากรรม การเรียกร้อง และความรับผิดอื่น ๆ

#### 4\. การแบ่งปันข้อมูล

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. และ WEBTOON Entertainment Inc. ในฐานะที่เป็นผู้ควบคุมข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านร่วมกัน จะแบ่งปันข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลกันเมื่อจำเป็นเพื่อให้บริการได้อย่างมีประสิทธิภาพและถูกต้องตามกฎหมายที่ใช้บังคับ เราจะเปิดเผยหรือแบ่งปันข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลที่เกี่ยวข้องกับท่านผ่านบริการตามที่อธิบายไว้ด้านล่างนี้  
\- **ข้อมูลที่เปิดเผยต่อสาธารณะ**: ทุกคนรวมถึงผู้ที่ไม่มีบัญชีกับเรา สามารถเห็นข้อมูลที่ท่านเลือกที่จะให้เปิดเผยต่อสาธารณะ ข้อมูลดังกล่าวอาจประกอบด้วย ชื่อเล่น รูปโปรไฟล์ ประวัติโดยย่อ ลิงก์สื่อสังคมออนไลน์ เว็บไซต์ ข้อมูลอื่น ๆ บนโปรไฟล์สาธารณะของท่าน และข้อมูลหรือเนื้อหาใด ๆ ที่ท่านแบ่งปันกับสาธารณะ  
\- **ผู้ให้บริการ**: เราอาจเปิดเผยข้อมูลของท่านต่อบริษัทที่ให้บริการในนามของเรา เช่น บริษัทที่ช่วยพัฒนาและดำเนินระบบต่าง ๆ ที่ใช้ในการให้บริการกับศูนย์ติดต่อลูกค้า ตลอดจนกิจกรรมการดูแลลูกค้า การโฆษณา (รวมถึงการโฆษณาแบบเฉพาะบุคคลบนเว็บไซต์ของเรา เว็บไซต์ของบุคคลภายนอก หรือแพลตฟอร์มออนไลน์) การทำแบบสำรวจความพึงพอใจของลูกค้า การเรียกเก็บเงิน หรือการส่งอีเมลในนามของเรา ทั้งนี้ ข้อกำหนดของสัญญาจะจำกัดสิทธิบริษัทเหล่านี้ในการใช้ข้อมูลของท่านเพื่อวัตถุประสงค์อื่นที่นอกเหนือจากการให้บริการในนามของเรา  
ในฐานะผู้ให้บริการตามข้อบังคับทางกฎหมาย ผู้ให้บริการดังกล่าวอาจสามารถเข้าถึงข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านเพื่อให้บริการและ/หรือปฏิบัติตามภาระผูกพันที่เกิดจากความสัมพันธ์ทางกฎหมายระหว่างเราและผู้ให้บริการภายนอกดังกล่าว ไม่ว่าจะในกรณีใด ๆ เราและผู้ให้บริการเหล่านั้นได้ลงนามผูกพันในสัญญาการรักษาความลับและการคุ้มครองข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลซึ่งเป็นไปตามบทบัญญัติของกฎหมายคุ้มครองข้อมูลในปัจจุบัน  
\- **พันธมิตรการชำระเงิน (Payment Partners)**: ข้อมูลการชำระเงินและการซื้อจะถูกเก็บรวบรวมและประมวลผลโดยพันธมิตรการชำระเงิน เพื่อวัตถุประสงค์ในการประมวลผลการชำระเงินและป้องกันการฉ้อโกง  
\- **คู่ค้าทางโฆษณา** เราอาจแชร์ข้อมูลของคุณเพื่อจะแสดงโฆษณาที่เกี่ยวข้องกับคุณมากขึ้นและช่วยวัดประสิทธิภาพของโฆษณา  
\- **คู่ค้าทางการตลาด** เราสามารถแบ่งปันข้อมูลของคุณเพื่อให้คุณสามารถเข้าร่วมในโปรโมชันต่าง ๆ ของเรา รวมไปถึงให้เราโปรโมตบริการของเราบนแพลตฟอร์มอื่น ๆ และวัดประสิทธิภาพของกิจกรรมทางการตลาดของเรา  
\- **บริษัทในเครือของเรา** เราอาจแบ่งปันข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของคุณกับบริษัทย่อยของเราเพื่อวัตถุประสงค์ที่อธิบายไว้ในนโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวนี้  
\- **บุคคลอื่นตามที่กฎหมายกำหนดหรือตามความจำเป็นในการคุ้มครองบริการของเรา**: เราอาจจำเป็นต้องเปิดเผยข้อมูลของท่านต่อบุคคลอื่น ๆ ในกรณีดังต่อไปนี้  
\- เพื่อปฏิบัติตามกฎหมายหรือดำเนินการตามกระบวนการทางกฎหมายที่จำเป็น (เช่น หมายค้น หรือคำสั่งศาลอื่น ๆ)  
\- เพื่อตรวจสอบหรือบังคับการปฏิบัติตามนโยบายที่กำกับบริการของเรา และ  
\- เพื่อปกป้องสิทธิ ทรัพย์สิน หรือรักษาความปลอดภัย หรือปฏิบัติตามกฎหมายคุ้มครองข้อมูล หรือคุ้มครองบริษัทในเครือ พันธมิตรทางธุรกิจ หรือลูกค้าที่เกี่ยวข้องใด ๆ ของเรา  
\- **บุคคลอื่นที่เกี่ยวข้องกับธุรกรรม**: เราอาจเปิดเผยข้อมูลของท่านต่อบุคคลภายนอกอันเป็นส่วนหนึ่งของการควบรวม การโอน การได้มา หรือการขายกิจการ ที่เกิดขึ้นจริงหรือวางแผนไว้ หรือในกรณีของการล้มละลาย  
\- **บุคคลอื่น ๆ ที่ได้รับความยินยอมจากท่านหรือตามคำขอของท่าน**: นอกเหนือจากการเปิดเผยข้อมูลตามที่อธิบายไว้ในนโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวนี้ เราอาจแบ่งปันข้อมูลเกี่ยวกับท่านกับบุคคลภายนอก เมื่อท่านให้ความยินยอมหรือร้องขอให้มีการแบ่งปันข้อมูลดังกล่าวเป็นกรณีเฉพาะ  
\- **การเชื่อมโยงไปยังเว็บไซต์ อุปกรณ์ แอปพลิเคชัน และฟีเจอร์อื่น ๆ**: บริการอาจอนุญาตให้มีการเชื่อมต่อกับเว็บไซต์ อุปกรณ์ แอปพลิเคชัน และฟีเจอร์อื่น ๆ ที่อาจดำเนินการเป็นอิสระจากเรา และอาจมีนโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวที่ใช้บังคับแยกต่างหาก ซึ่งเราขอแนะนำให้ท่านศึกษาโดยละเอียด ในกรณีที่เราไม่ได้เป็นเจ้าของหรือควบคุมเว็บไซต์ อุปกรณ์ แอปพลิเคชัน หรือฟีเจอร์อื่น ๆ ที่เชื่อมโยงใด ๆ ดังกล่าว เราจะไม่รับผิดชอบต่อแนวทางปฏิบัติด้านเนื้อหา การใช้งาน หรือความเป็นส่วนตัวของเว็บไซต์ อุปกรณ์ แอปพลิเคชัน หรือฟีเจอร์อื่น ๆ

#### 5\. การเก็บรักษาข้อมูลส่วนบุคคล

เราจะดำเนินตามขั้นตอนที่เหมาะสมเพื่อให้แน่ใจว่า เราประมวลผลและเก็บรักษาข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลเกี่ยวกับท่านตามหลักการดังต่อไปนี้  
\- ใช้ระยะเวลาให้น้อยที่สุดในประมวลผลและเก็บรักษาที่ข้อมูลเกี่ยวกับท่านเพื่อให้บริการแก่ท่าน  
\- เป็นไปตามที่กำหนดไว้ในกฎหมาย สัญญา หรือภาระผูกพันตามกฎหมายของเรา (เช่น กฎหมายภาษีอากร) หรือ  
\- เท่าที่จำเป็นเพื่อวัตถุประสงค์ในการเก็บรวบรวมหรือประมวลผล หรือนานกว่านั้นหากจำเป็นภายใต้สัญญาใด ๆ และกฎหมายที่ใช้บังคับ หรือประมวลผลและเก็บรักษาข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลเกี่ยวกับท่านในรูปแบบที่ไม่สามารถระบุตัวบุคคลเพื่อวัตถุประสงค์ทางสถิติภายใต้มาตรการรักษาความปลอดภัยที่เหมาะสม  
ดังนั้น เราจะเก็บรักษาข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านไว้เท่าที่จำเป็นเพื่อวัตถุประสงค์ของการเก็บรวบรวมข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลนั้น และเพื่อปฏิบัติตามข้อกำหนดทางกฎหมาย ทางการเงิน ทางธุรกิจ หรือการรายงาน เมื่อเราไม่จำเป็นต้องใช้ข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลนั้นอีกต่อไป เราจะลบหรือทำลายข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลดังกล่าวอย่างปลอดภัย  
เราจะเก็บรักษาข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลที่เก็บรวบรวมไว้จนกว่าอายุความความรับผิดทางกฎหมายใด ๆ ที่เกิดขึ้นจะสิ้นสุดลง

#### 6\. สิทธิของท่าน

ท่านเป็นเจ้าของข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านเอง ท่านมีสิทธิขอให้เราแจ้งรายละเอียดเกี่ยวกับข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลที่เราเก็บรวบรวม หรือขอให้เราแก้ไขข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลให้ถูกต้องได้ โดยมีรายละเอียดเกี่ยวกับสิทธิของท่านดังต่อไปนี้ ทั้งนี้ ขึ้นอยู่กับประเทศที่ท่านอาศัยอยู่

**สิทธิของท่านในการเข้าถึง**: ท่านมีสิทธิสอบถามว่าเราใช้หรือเก็บรักษาข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านหรือไม่ อีกทั้งยังมีสิทธิขอสำเนาข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านได้  
**สิทธิของท่านในการแก้ไข**: ท่านมีสิทธิขอให้เราแก้ไขข้อมูลที่ท่านเห็นว่าไม่ถูกต้อง และมีสิทธิแก้ไขข้อมูลให้ครบถ้วน  
**สิทธิของท่านในการลบข้อมูล**: ท่านมีสิทธิขอให้เราลบข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่าน ในกรณีที่ (1) เราไม่จำเป็นต้องใช้ข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลนั้นอีกต่อไป (2) ท่านยินยอมให้ใช้ข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลนั้นในตอนแรก แต่ปัจจุบันท่านได้เพิกถอนความยินยอมดังกล่าวแล้ว (3) ท่านได้คัดค้านการใช้ข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลนั้น และผลประโยชน์ของท่านมีมากกว่าผลประโยชน์ของบริษัทของเรา (4) เราได้เก็บรวบรวมหรือใช้ข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลนั้นโดยมิชอบด้วยกฎหมาย และ/หรือ (5) เรามีภาระผูกพันตามกฎหมายในการลบข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่าน  
**สิทธิของท่านในการระงับการประมวลผล**: ท่านมีสิทธิขอให้เราจำกัดการประมวลผลข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่าน ในกรณีที่ (1) ท่านได้คัดค้านเรื่องความถูกต้องของข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่าน (2) ท่านได้คัดค้านการใช้ข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่าน (3) เราได้ประมวลผลข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านโดยมิชอบด้วยกฎหมาย โดยที่ท่านไม่ประสงค์ที่จะลบข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลดังกล่าว และ/หรือ (4) เราไม่จำเป็นต้องใช้ข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านอีกต่อไป แต่ท่านประสงค์ที่จะให้เราเก็บรักษาไว้เพื่อแก้ต่างหรือใช้สิทธิในการเรียกร้องทางกฎหมาย  
**สิทธิของท่านในการคัดค้านการประมวลผล**: ท่านมีสิทธิคัดค้านการประมวลผลข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่าน หากเรานำข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านไปใช้ (1) ในการปฏิบัติหน้าที่เพื่อประโยชน์สาธารณะ (2) เพื่อประโยชน์ที่ชอบด้วยกฎหมายของเรา (3) เพื่อการศึกษาวิจัยทางวิทยาศาสตร์หรือประวัติศาสตร์ หรือเพื่อวัตถุประสงค์ทางสถิติ หรือ (4) เพื่อการตลาดแบบตรง  
**สิทธิของท่านในการขอโอนย้าย**: สิทธินี้มีผลบังคับใช้กับข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลที่ท่านให้ไว้กับเรา และการประมวลผลนั้นดำเนินการด้วยวิธีการอัตโนมัติตามความยินยอมของท่านหรือที่ได้ทำภายใต้บังคับของสัญญา ท่านมีสิทธิขอให้เราโอนข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านไปยังองค์กรอื่น หรือให้ข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลนั้นกับท่านโดยตรงในรูปแบบที่สามารถอ่านหรือใช้งานโดยทั่วไปได้ด้วยเครื่องมือหรืออุปกรณ์ เว้นแต่โดยสภาพทางเทคนิคไม่สามารถทำได้  
**สิทธิของท่านในการถอนความยินยอม**: ท่านมีสิทธิถอนความยินยอมของท่านได้ทุกเมื่อเฉพาะในกรณีที่การประมวลผลนั้นอาศัยความยินยอมของท่าน โดยการถอนความยินยอมนั้นจะไม่ส่งผลกระทบต่อความชอบด้วยกฎหมายของการประมวลผลที่อาศัยความยินยอมก่อนการเพิกถอนความยินยอมดังกล่าว  
**สิทธิของท่านในการร้องเรียนต่อหน่วยงานกำกับดูแล**: ท่านมีสิทธิร้องเรียนต่อหน่วยงานกำกับดูแลที่เกี่ยวข้อง หากเห็นว่าการประมวลผลข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านไม่เป็นไปตามกฎหมายที่ใช้บังคับ

#### 7\. การใช้สิทธิและตัวเลือกของท่าน

หากท่านประสงค์จะใช้สิทธิใด ๆ ข้างต้น หรือส่งคำขอใด ๆ โปรดติดต่อเราตามรายละเอียดในหัวข้อ ติดต่อเรา (Contact Us) (ข้อ 10 ของนโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวนี้) อย่างไรก็ตาม หากกฎหมายอนุญาตให้ทำได้ เราอาจเรียกเก็บค่าธรรมเนียมในจำนวนเล็กน้อยสำหรับการดำเนินการตามคำขอใช้สิทธิของท่าน เราอาจปฏิเสธที่จะดำเนินการตามคำขอที่ซ้ำซ้อนเกินสมควร หรือที่จำเป็นต้องใช้ความพยายามทางเทคนิคที่เกินสมควร หรือที่จะกระทบต่อความเป็นส่วนตัวของผู้อื่น หรือกฎหมายท้องถิ่นไม่ได้กำหนดให้สิทธิเข้าถึงข้อมูล ทั้งนี้ ภายใต้กฎหมายที่ใช้บังคับ

ท่านมีสิทธิเข้าถึงหรือแก้ไขข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านที่ลงทะเบียนกับเราได้ตลอดเวลาผ่านทางหน้า "บัญชี (Account)" หรือ "โปรไฟล์ครีเอเตอร์ (Creator Profile)"

ท่านมีสิทธิขอให้เราลบข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านโดยการลบบัญชีของท่านเมื่อใดก็ได้ หากท่านมีการ์ตูนชุด (Series) ที่เผยแพร่อยู่บน แคนวาส (CANVAS) ท่านจะต้องลบการ์ตูนชุดดังกล่าวออกก่อนที่จะลบบัญชีของท่าน เมื่อท่านลบบัญชีของท่านแล้ว โปรไฟล์บัญชีและประวัติการสมัครสมาชิกของท่านจะถูกลบโดยถาวรและไม่สามารถกู้คืนได้ ทั้งนี้ ข้อมูลภาษีใด ๆ ที่ได้ส่งให้เราจะถูกเก็บรักษาไว้เป็นระยะเวลาหนึ่งตามที่กฎหมายและข้อบังคับทางการเงินกำหนดไว้

หากท่านประสงค์ที่จะเปลี่ยนแปลงการตั้งค่าของท่านเกี่ยวกับการสื่อสารของเรา (รวมถึงการสื่อสารทางการตลาด) ท่านสามารถเปลี่ยนการตั้งค่าการสื่อสาร (Communication Preferences) ของท่านได้ที่หน้า "บัญชี (Account)" หรือหน้า "การตั้งค่า (Settings)" อีกทั้งท่านยังสามารถยกเลิกรับข่าวสารการตลาดทางอีเมลของเราได้ทุกเมื่อ โดยคลิกลิงก์ "ยกเลิกสมาชิก (Unsubscribe)" ที่ด้านล่างของอีเมล

ท่านสามารถจัดการการใช้คุกกี้ทางเลือก (Optional Cookies) ได้โดยคลิก "การตั้งค่าคุกกี้ (Cookie Settings)" ที่จะแสดงขึ้นเมื่อท่านเปิดแอปพลิเคชันหรือเข้าเยี่ยมชมเว็บไซต์ และเมื่อใดก็ได้ผ่านทางเมนูการตั้งค่าคุกกี้ (Cookie Settings) หากต้องการทราบข้อมูลเพิ่มเติมเกี่ยวกับแนวทางการใช้คุกกี้ที่เก็บรวบรวมไว้ โปรดศึกษา[นโยบายคุกกี้ (Cookie Policy)](https://www.webtoons.com/th/terms/cookiePolicy) ของเราเพิ่มเติม นอกจากนี้ ท่านยังสามารถจำกัดหรือปิดใช้งานคุกกี้บางประเภทได้โดยเข้าไปที่ [https://www.allaboutcookies.org/](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/) หรือ [https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1)

#### 8\. เราคุ้มครองข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลอย่างไริ

เราให้ความคุ้มครองข้อมูลของท่านอย่างจริงจัง และดำเนินการตามมาตรการรักษาความปลอดภัยที่ออกแบบไว้สำหรับการคุ้มครองข้อมูลเกี่ยวเนื่องกับบริการ การส่งข้อมูลทางอินเทอร์เน็ตไม่ได้ปลอดภัยอย่างสมบูรณ์ แม้ว่าเราจะพยายามอย่างสุดความสามารถในการคุ้มครองข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่าน แต่เราก็ไม่อาจรับประกันความปลอดภัยของข้อมูลของท่านในระหว่างที่ถูกส่งมาให้เราได้ เราจะไม่รับผิดหรือรับผิดชอบต่อการเปิดเผยข้อมูลของท่าน อันเนื่องมาจากข้อผิดพลาดในระหว่างการส่งข้อมูล การเข้าถึงของบุคคลภายนอกโดยปราศจากอำนาจ หรือสาเหตุอื่น ๆ ที่อยู่นอกเหนือการควบคุมของเรา ทั้งนี้ เท่าที่สามารถทำได้ภายใต้ขอบเขตของกฎหมายที่ใช้บังคับ

ท่านมีบทบาทสำคัญในการเก็บรักษาข้อมูลของท่านให้ปลอดภัย ท่านไม่ควรเปิดเผยชื่อผู้ใช้งาน (Username) หรือรหัสผ่าน (Password) ของบัญชีของท่านให้ผู้อื่นทราบ หากท่านมีเหตุให้เชื่อได้ว่าบัญชีของท่านไม่ปลอดภัยอีกต่อไป โปรดติดต่อเราโดยทันที

#### 9\. ข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของผู้เยาว์

บริการได้ถูกออกแบบสำหรับผู้ใช้ทุกวัย หากจำเป็นต้องได้รับความยินยอมจากบิดาหรือมารดา (หรือผู้ใช้อำนาจปกครองที่มีอำนาจกระทำการแทนผู้เยาว์) ในการประมวลผลข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของผู้เยาว์ตามกฎหมายที่ใช้บังคับ เราจะประมวลผลข้อมูลดังกล่าวก็ต่อเมื่อได้รับความยินยอมจากบิดาหรือมารดา (หรือผู้ใช้อำนาจปกครองที่มีอำนาจกระทำการแทนผู้เยาว์) ตามกระบวนการที่กฎหมายกำหนดไว้

#### 10\. ติดต่อเรา (Contact Us)

\- หากท่านมีคำถาม ข้อกังวล หรือข้อซักถามใด ๆ เกี่ยวกับนโยบาย (Policies) การจัดการข้อมูลส่วนบุคคล ท่านสามารถติดต่อแผนกจัดการข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของเราได้ที่[ฝ่ายดูแลลูกค้า (Customer Care)](https://contact-cc.line.me/serviceId/12379/th/?continue_without_login=true)  
\- ท่านสามารถติดต่อเราได้โดยส่งอีเมลถึงเจ้าหน้าที่คุ้มครองข้อมูลส่วนบุคคล (DPO) ของเราตามที่อยู่อีเมล [dpo@webtoonscorp.com](mailto:dpo@webtoonscorp.com)  
\- ในกรณีใด ๆ ก็ตาม ท่านสามารถติดต่อเราเป็นลายลักษณ์อักษรได้ตามที่อยู่ด้านล่างนี้  
  
NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.  
TechONE Tower1 11-12F,  
131, Bundangnaegok-ro, Bundang-gu,  
Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do,  
Republic of Korea  
  
เนื่องจาก NAVER WEBTOON Ltd. WEBTOON Entertainment Inc. จะดำเนินการร่วมกันเมื่อจำเป็นในการปฏิบัติตามสิทธิ คำขอ หรือข้อร้องเรียนของท่าน ท่านจึงสามารถติดต่อเราได้ที่ WEBTOON Entertainment Inc. ด้วยเช่นกัน  
WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.  
5700 Wilshire Blvd Suite 220,  
Los Angeles, CA 90036  
United States

#### 11\. การเชื่อมโยงไปยังเว็บไซต์อื่น

ท่านอาจระบุไฮเปอร์ลิงก์ (Hyperlinks) ไปยังเว็บไซต์ขององค์กรอื่น ๆ บนเว็บไซต์ของเราหรือในเนื้อหาที่เราส่งให้ท่าน (เช่น อีเมลหรือกิจกรรมส่งเสริมการขาย) โปรดทราบว่านโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวนี้ไม่ครอบคลุมถึงแนวทางการประมวลผลข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลของท่านโดยบริษัทอื่น เราขอแนะนำให้ท่านศึกษานโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวที่ใช้บังคับกับเว็บไซต์อื่น ๆ ดังกล่าวเพิ่มเติม

#### 12\. การปรับปรุงนโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวของเรา

นโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวนี้อาจได้รับการปรับปรุงเพื่อให้เป็นไปตามการเปลี่ยนแปลงของแนวทางปฏิบัติเกี่ยวกับข้อมูลส่วนบุคคลที่เกี่ยวข้องกับบริการของเรา หรือการเปลี่ยนแปลงของกฎหมายที่ใช้บังคับ โดยเราจะประกาศผ่านทางบริการของเราเพื่อแจ้งให้ท่านทราบล่วงหน้าเกี่ยวกับการเปลี่ยนแปลงที่สำคัญในนโยบายความเป็นส่วนตัวของเรา และระบุวันที่ปรับปรุงล่าสุดไว้ด้านบนของประกาศ

### 台灣 WEBTOON™ 隱私權政策要點

最後更新：2024年3月26日

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.（包括其子公司，以下合稱「**我們**」或「**我們的**」）尊重您對個人隱私權的保障，凡是我們透過WEBTOON應用程式和/或網站、投稿新星專區 （合稱「**本服務**」）所蒐集的個人資料，均有本隱私權政策的適用。

#### 隱私權政策概述

在本隱私權政策中，我們說明透過本服務處理的個人資料種類、我們如何利用資料、我們與誰分享資料，以及您在使用資料和行使權利時有何選擇。我們亦說明我們為保護資料安全所採取的措施，並告知您如何就我們隱私權實行措施來聯繫我們。您將從以下找到我們隱私權政策關鍵資訊的摘要，如欲知悉更多我們如何處理您資料的資訊，請點選標題或繼續向下閱讀。

### WEBTOON™ 隱私權政策 台灣策

#### 1\. 資料控管者

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.及WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.共享處理個人資料的控制權，並作為您個人資料的共同控管者相互分享資料，以有效率地提供本服務並遵守可適用的法律。

在任何時刻，您可透過以下地址以書面聯繫我們：  
  
NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.  
TechONE Tower1 11-12F,  
131, Bundangnaegok-ro, Bundang-gu,  
Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do,  
Republic of Korea.  
或  
  
WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.  
5700 Wilshire Blvd Suite 220,  
Los Angeles, CA 90036  
United States

#### 2\. 我們蒐集的資料

伴隨本服務之提供，謹蒐集以下個人資料：

##### 您直接提供的資料

當您使用我們的服務，於資料蒐集時被告知隱私權訊息後，您可提供之您的個人資料，例如：  
\- 聯絡資訊：當使用者依據使用者所在管轄地可適用法規經認定為兒童時，我們會需要使用者姓名及法定代理人的電子郵件地址，並根據您所在管轄地規定取得法定代理人的同意。此外，當您參加活動或促銷，我們會請您提供姓名、電話、地址、電子郵件地址及任何其他寄送獎品及回應請求所必須的資訊。  
\- 帳戶資訊：當您建立您自己的帳戶並登入時，我們可能需要您的出生日期、暱稱、電子郵件地址和密碼。此外，當您登入第三方帳戶或使用我們的個人檔案時，我們可能會要求您提供暱稱或個人照片等資訊。  
\- 調查資訊：當您參加我們的調查或意見調查，我們會請您提供姓名、電話號碼、性別及任何其他從事調查或提供獎品時會合理要求的資訊。  
\- 圖像資訊：當您使用撕漫濾鏡時，我們可能會蒐集照片及有關圖像的資訊，包含識別圖像內的物品和風景，以及照片中臉部和身體特徵。經識別的圖像資訊將不會連結您的帳號，僅適用於顯現撕漫濾鏡效果及分辨不當圖像。我們不會將該資訊來做為識別特定個人資訊的用途，且也不會將該資訊用於培訓或改進我們的技術。  
\- 客服中心：為答覆您向我們「客服中心」所提出的聯繫，我們會蒐集任何您選擇提供的資訊，例如請求或是查詢。當您與我們客服人員或其他人員溝通時，您的對話內容將通過您的電子郵件向我們的系統傳遞。  
\- 個資識別標識，例如專有的個人識別標識（例如(i) 裝置識別碼（例如：cookies、網路信標、像素標籤），(ii) 行動廣告識別資訊和類似技術，(iii) 客戶編號、獨特假名或使用者別名，(iv) 電話號碼和其他形式的永久或隨機識別碼），網路標識和IP位址及其他相類似可資識別之標識。

\[創作者須知\]

當您使用[投稿新星專區](https://www.webtoons.com/zh-hant/challenge/)和/或廣告收益共享計畫時，我們可能需要蒐集以下額外資料：  
\- 作家個版：我們會請您提供您在創作者檔案頁面所已經自願公開分享的資訊，包括個人資料照片、自我介紹、社群媒體連結、網站及其他資訊。  
\- 我們會請您將PayPal帳號或Patreon帳號連結至本服務。  
\- 我們會請您提供uTip帳號以提供獎品或紅利。  
\- 廣告收益支付資訊：如您選擇提供您的PayPal帳戶，我們會請您提供額外資訊，例如您的名稱（法定名稱/商業別稱）、全名/商業名稱、國家、住址、地址、郵遞區號、電子郵件、簽名或稅籍帳號（或社會安全碼，如果適用）以作為稅務處理之用。

\[WEBTOON翻譯使用者須知\]

\- 當您使用[WEBTOON翻譯](https://translate.webtoons.com/)，我們可能需要蒐集以下額外資訊：  
\- 個人資料資訊：我們會請您提供您在個人資料頁面所已經自願公開分享的資訊，包括個人資料照片、暱稱、使用者網站的網址、地點及您所選擇的語言。  
\- 團隊經理申請資訊：如您申請為團隊經理，我們會請您提供有關「我的個人資料」之網址、您所選擇的語言及其他翻譯經歷。

##### 透過cookies及相似科技蒐集的資訊

\- 我們及第三方會使用cookies、網路信標、像素標籤及其他追蹤科技（以下我們合稱「cookies」）來幫助我們彙整數據資料，以提升您使用本服務的使用體驗、儲存您的喜好並提供您客製化優惠，這些cookies會隨著時間用於追蹤您不同設備及網站。多數網頁瀏覽器會自動接受cookies及session ID，但您可透過瀏覽器選項或Cookie設定做出適當選擇以停用cookies。請留意，如此一來我們服務的功能可能會受到限制。  
為瞭解更多或我們如何使用cookies進行蒐集，請參考我們的Cookie政策。為更加瞭解cookies，包括如何知悉我們設定的cookies，請參訪[www.aboutcookies.org/](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/www.aboutcookies.org/)或[www.allaboutcookies.org/](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/www.allaboutcookies.org/)。

##### 您使用本服務的資訊

除您提供的資訊外，我們將透過您設備上的軟體和其他方式，蒐集您使用我們服務的資訊，我們將蒐集：  
\- 服務使用資訊：您與服務的互動、日期及使用本服務的次數及任何服務使用資訊，例如閱讀種類偏好、留言或喜好、金幣及免費通行證的餘額、廣告資訊，包括購買及交易歷史、近期閱覽、訂閱歷史、下載歷史及參與活動、促銷及/或競賽資訊。  
\- 與競賽籌劃和/或任何促銷活動有關的資訊：參與日期、對競賽內容所作回應和所供獎品性質；  
\- 設備及登入資訊：設備及登入資訊例如設備型號、操作系統版本、IP位址、登入設定、IP位址所在國資訊、網址及網路型態；及  
\- 交易/購買細節：我們不會蒐集或處理任何有關您的付款資訊（例如：信用卡資訊），該類資訊只會由Apple應用程式商店、Google Play商店及PayPal蒐集及處理；Apple應用程式商店、Google Play商店及PayPal唯一會與我們分享的資訊是交易和購買資訊（例如：交易號碼、購買記錄），該類資訊只會基於驗證交易的目的而處理。  
\- 個人化推算：我們將根據您使用服務的習慣或透過廣告合作夥伴推算您感興趣的主題或偏好及性別。

##### 透過第三方分析服務所蒐集的資訊

\- 我們可能會透過本服務蒐集您的個人資料，包括您不同時間透過第三方網站、設備、應用程式及其他線上功能與服務等，在我們網站和連結設備上從事的線上活動。我們會在本服務中使用第三方分析服務，因此我們所取得資訊會提供予或由該服務提供商直接蒐集，或提供予其他相關第三方，用作例如評估服務之使用或幫助管理本服務。

#### 3.我們如何使用所蒐集的資料

我們可能會基於以下目的使用上述蒐集的資料：

\[使用者及創作者須知\]

\- 識別及驗證您的身份，以及管理您的帳戶  
\- 提供您所要求的服務或功能，例如回應您透過本服務提出的要求、問題及指示；  
\- 進行必要的調查及分析以改善本服務；  
\- 向您寄送競賽及活動的資訊及獎品；  
\- 當使用者購買產品或使用付費服務時，處理付款及帳單事宜；  
\- 提供客製推薦功能，例如根據您的年齡和/或使用服務習慣（如您最常瀏覽的網站）推薦相關內容，以及以您選擇感興趣的主題爲您推薦個人化內容；  
\- 提供可能包含个性化或定向（或基于兴趣）广告的广告。  
\- 透過電子郵件或產品內建通知（例如：彈出通知、推播通知）向您寄送您通訊偏好所控制，且與本服務相關之通訊內容；  
\- 監控及分析與我們的產品及服務有關的趨勢、使用及活動；  
\- 創造去識別化、匿名化或彙總的資料；  
\- 傳輸或保護數位內容；  
\- 驗證年齡並提供適合年齡的內容和體驗。  
\- 確保我們服務的資訊安全；  
\- 防範、識別及防止詐欺及其他犯罪活動、索賠及其他責任；  
\- 產出與本服務使用有關的統計數據；  
\- 確保及監控本服務的有效性及可用性，以改善網站及應用程式的效能；  
\- 遵循及執行可適用的法律規定、我們的法定義務（例如：稅法）、相關產業標準及本公司政策，包括本隱私權政策；  
\- 驗證交易及防止詐欺及濫用行為；  
\- 回應您的詢問以及於必要時寄送使用者重要通知；和  
\- 執行於資料蒐集時所向您說明的任何其他目的。

\[投稿新星專區和/或廣告收益共享計畫創作者須知\]

除上述目的外，我們可能會基於以下額外目的，向[投稿新星專區](https://www.webtoons.com/zh-hant/challenge)和/或[廣告收益共享計畫](https://www.webtoons.com/en/terms/adRevenueSharingPolicy)的創作者蒐集資料：  
\- 提供調查參與者、競賽參與者或獲勝者獎勵、獎金或發送獎品；  
\- 驗證您的身分以遵守可適用的聯邦法律；  
\- 提供使用者廣告收益共享計畫；  
\- 向您寄送您的電子郵件偏好所控制，且與您作品或使用相關的電子郵件；  
\- 答覆您的問題；  
\- 了解您如何使用本服務及創造更佳的廣告收益共享計畫；  
\- 產出與本服務使用有關的統計數據；  
\- 進行研究及開發，以改善廣告收益共享計畫及開發未來新產品。  
\- 遵循及執行可適用的法律規定、我們的法定義務（例如：稅法）、相關產業標準及本公司政策，包括本隱私權政策；  
\- 防止詐欺及廣告收益共享計畫的濫用，及防止其他犯罪活動、索賠及責任；

#### 4\. 資料共享

NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.及WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.於必要時將作為您個人資料的共同控制者相互分享資訊，以有效率地提供本服務並遵守可適用的法律。我們透過本服務揭露或共享與您有關的個人資料如下所述：  
\- **公開資料**：任何人都可以看到您自願註冊與公眾分享的資料，包括那些沒有註冊帳戶的人。這可能包括您的暱稱、個人資料照片、簡介、社群媒體連結、網站、您公開個人資料上的其他資訊及任何您與公眾分享的資料或內容。  
\- **服務供應商**：我們可能會向代表我們提供服務的公司揭露您的資料，例如協助我們開發和營運本服務有關客戶聯絡中心，和客戶關懷活動、廣告（包括在我們網站、第三方網站或其他線上平台的客製化廣告）、執行客戶滿意度調查、寄發帳單或代表我們寄送電子郵件的公司。這些實體受有合約條款的限制，無法將您的資料用於為我們提供服務以外的目的。  
\- 作為符合法律規定的服務供應商，這些供應商可能會取得您的個人資料，以提供服務和/或遵守上述第三方與我們之間法律關係所產生的義務。無論如何，我們與這些服務供應商均簽署相應的保密及資料保護協議，完全遵循現行對資料保護的立法規定。  
\- **付款合作夥伴**：付款及購買資訊由付款合作夥伴蒐集及處理，用於處理付款及反詐欺的目的。  
\- **廣告合作夥伴**：為了向您提供更加符合個人化興趣推薦的廣告，並提高廣告的效率，我們可能會與第三方共享您的資料。  
\- **行銷合作夥伴**：為了確保您能夠順利參與我們的行銷活動以及在其他平台推廣我們的服務，並提高行銷活動的效率。我們可能會與第三方共享您的資料。  
\- **相關企業**：依照隱私政策所述之目的，我們可能會與子公司共享您的資料。  
\- **法律要求或為保護本服務所需的其他機構**：在某些情況下，我們會將您的資料揭露給其他機構：  
\- 以遵循法律或回應強制性法律程序（例如搜索票或其他法院命令）；  
\- 以驗證或遵守適用於本服務的政策；和  
\- 為了保護我們的權利、財產或安全，或者根據資料保護法規，保護我們的附屬機構、商業夥伴或客戶。  
\- **與交易有關的其他各方**：在實際或計劃中的合併、轉讓、收購或出售過程中，或於破產的情形下，我們可能會將您的資料揭露予第三方。  
\- **您同意或要求的其他各方**：除了本隱私權政策中所描述的揭露對象外，當您個別同意或要求進行資料共享時，我們可能會與第三方共享您的資料。  
\- **連結到其他網站、裝置、應用程式及功能**：本服務可能會提供具連結至其他網站、裝置、應用程式及其他功能的能力，這些網站、裝置、應用程式及其他功能可能會獨立於我們運作，並且可能擁有自己的隱私權聲明或政策，我們強烈建議您審閱其內容。於任何其他連結的網站、裝置、應用程式或其他功能不屬於我們所有或控制的情形下，我們對其內容、使用或隱私政策概不負責。

#### 5\. 個人資料的保存

我們將採取適當步驟來確保我們根據以下邏輯處理及保存您的個人資料：  
\- 在資料得提供您所需服務下所需的最短保存期間；  
\- 依據法律、合約或我們的法定義務（例如稅法）所要求；或  
\- 只限於蒐集、處理資料的目的所必需的時間內保存，或依據合約及適用法律的要求延長保存期間，或以匿名形式進行統計目的的情況下，且均採取適當的保護措施。  
\- 因此，我們僅於蒐集目的所需期間內留存您的個人資料，並遵循法律、財務、業務及申報規定。當我們不再需要您的個人資料時，我們將安全地刪除或銷毀之。  
  
我們將保存蒐集到的數據，直到因此產生的任何法律責任屆期為止。

#### 6\. 您的權利

您的個人資料歸您所有，根據您所在的管轄地，您可要求我們提供所蒐集資訊的細節，您亦可要求我們更正任何不正確的資訊。您的權利說明如下：

**您的接近使用權**：您有權利詢問我們是否正在使用或儲存您的個人資料。您也可以要求我們提供您個人資料的複製本。  
**您的更正權**：您有權利要求我們更正您認為不正確的資訊。您也有權利將您認為不完整的資訊使其補充完整。  
**您的刪除權**：於下列情形中，您有權利要求我們刪除您的個人資料：(i)我們不再需要您的個人資料，(ii) 您原本同意我們使用您的個人資料，但現已撤回您的同意，(iii)您反對我們使用您的個人資料，且您的利益比我們公司的利益更加重要，(iv)我們非法蒐集或使用您的個人資料，和/或(v)我們有刪除您個人資料的法定義務。  
**您的限制處理權**：於下列情形中，您有權利要求我們限制處理您的個人資料：(i)您對您個人資料的正確性提出質疑，(ii) 您反對我們使用您的個人資料，(iii)我們不顧您表達希望刪除的情況下，非法處理您的個人資料，和/或(iv) 我們不再需要您的個人資料，但您希望我們繼續保存，以作為抗辯或法律權利行使。  
**您的反對處理權**：您有權利反對處理您的個人資料，如果我們使用您的個人資料是基於以下目的：(i)為公共利益而執行的任務，(ii)我們的合法利益，(iii)科學或歷史研究或統計目的，或(iv)直接行銷。  
**您的資料可攜權**：這項權利適用於您提供給我們的個人資料，且該處理是基於您的同意或依據契約而自動化進行的情形。您有權利要求我們，在技術上可行的前提下，將您的個人資料移轉至另一個組織，或直接以可近用和機器可讀取的方式提供給您。  
**您也有權撤回同意**：在任何時候，如果處理係基於您的同意，且不影響撤回前基於該同意所為處理之合法性。  
**您有權向監管機關提出申訴**：如果您認為我們對您個人資料的處理違反可適用的法規，您可以向相關監管機關提出申訴。

#### 7\. 行使您的權利和您的選擇

如果您想行使上述權利，或您想提交您的請求，請參照[聯絡我們](#pp_10_zh_hant)一節（本隱私政策第10節）聯繫我們。然而，如果法律允許，我們可能會向您收取小額費用。根據可適用的法律，我們可能會拒絕處理不合理的重複請求、技術支援不成比例的請求、危害他人隱私或當地法律未要求的近用。

您可以隨時透過「帳戶」或「創作者帳戶」頁面來近用或更正您在我們這裡註冊所提供的個人資料。

您可以隨時要求我們刪除您的帳戶來刪除您的個人資料。如果您在投稿新星專區上有發表任何系列作品，您必須先刪除之，後才能刪除您的帳戶。一旦您刪除您的帳戶，您帳戶的個人資料和訂閱歷史將永久刪除，且無法復原。依據金融法規的要求，任何提交給我們的稅務資訊將被保留一段時間。

如果您想變更我們通訊（包括行銷通訊）的偏好設定，您可從「帳戶」頁面或「設定」頁面變更您的通訊偏好。您也可隨時透過點擊電子郵件底部的「取消訂閱」連結，來取消訂閱我們的電子郵件行銷訊息。

您可以透過點擊打開應用程式/訪問網站時顯示的「Cookie設定」方案，並隨時過Cookie設定來管理可選擇的cookies的使用。要瞭解更多關於我們如何使用蒐集的cookies的資訊，請參考我們的[Cookie政策](https://www.webtoons.com/zh-hant/terms/cookiePolicy)。您還可以透過以下連結，限制或禁止特定類型的cookies：[https://www.allaboutcookies.org/](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/)或[https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1)。

#### 8\. 我們如何保護個人資料

我們非常重視保護您的資訊，並嚴守措施保護我們所蒐集到的服務相關資訊。透過網路進行的資訊傳遞並非安全無虞，儘管我們將盡最大努力保護您的個人資料，但我們不能保證您的資訊在傳輸至我們時的安全性。在可適用法律允許的範圍內，我們不承擔由於傳遞錯誤、第三方未經授權的接近使用或其他我們不可控制原因所導致您的資訊遭到揭露的責任或義務。

您在保護您的資訊安全方面扮演著重要角色。您不應該與任何人分享您的帳戶的使用者名稱或密碼。如果您有理由相信您的帳戶不再安全，請立即聯絡我們。

#### 9\. 兒童的個人資料

我們的服務是為一般觀眾所設計。如果依據可適用的法律，處理兒童的個人資料須取得父母（或法定代理人）的同意，我們將按照法律規定的程序，於獲得父母（或法定代理人）的同意後處理這些資訊。

#### 10\. 聯絡我們

如果您對處理個人資料的政策有任何疑問、疑慮或問題，您可以寄至我們的個人資料管理部門：[客服中心](https://contact-cc.line.me/webtoon/zh-hant/)。  
您可透過寄送電子郵件至以下電子郵件地址給我們的資料保護官（DPO）來聯絡我們：[dpo@webtoonscorp.com](mailto:dpo@webtoonscorp.com)  
在任何時刻，您可透過以下地址以書面聯繫我們。  
  
NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.  
TechONE Tower1 11-12F,  
131, Bundangnaegok-ro, Bundang-gu,  
Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do,  
Republic of Korea.  
  
由於NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.和WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.會在必要時採取聯合行動，以符合您的權利、要求或申訴，您也可透過WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.聯絡我們：  
  
WEBTOON Entertainment Inc.  
5700 Wilshire Blvd Suite 220,  
Los Angeles, CA 90036  
United States

#### 11\. 與其他網站的連結

您可能會在我們的網站上或在我們提供給您的內容（例如，促銷電子郵件或活動）中發現連結其他組織網站的超連結。請注意，本隱私權政策並不包括其他公司將如何處理您的個人資料。我們建議您閱讀適用於這些其他網站的隱私權政策。

#### 12\. 我們的隱私權政策更新

本隱私權政策可能因與本服務有關之個人資料處理實行措施之變更而進行更新，或依照可適用法規而變更。於本隱私權政策進行重大變更前，我們將於本服務張貼公告，並於公告最上方顯示最近一次更新日期。

* * *

WEBTOON

Download WEBTOON now!

* |
* |
* |
* |
* |
* |
* |
* |
* |
* |
* change language

ⓒ NAVER WEBTOON Ltd.

WEBTOON
